LG TVs are able to be utilized as
eavesdropping listening devices in part
because of the advertising functionality
that's built into them. We were able to
retrieve plain text transcripts of voice
conversations and inputs from the TV.
Utilize the TV to record from a webcam
and from a microphone while the TV
appeared to be off. And it was clean
capture, too. All right, so the screen
appears to be off right now. Currently,
Wend and I are in a border. How are you?
>> Yikes. We were even able to capture
microphone audio while the TV was
unplugged from the network. This LG G5
TV has a microphone connected to it and
right now it's listening to me and
saving the information. In fact, we can
even unplug the network
and it's still listening to me and what
I'm saying is being stored by someone
with remote access to the TV. And then
we were able to excfiltrate that
recording via vulnerabilities after the
user reconnected the network.
>> And it's still listening to me.
>> No network.
>> What I'm saying is being stored by
someone with remote access to the TV.
>> But that requires an adversary, which
sounds scary. What we think is scarier
is LG itself. LG's first party
profit-seeking functionality prized deep
into your private life. The TV crawled
our entire network and found dozens of
unrelated devices, including
smartwatches and phones of our staff who
didn't even know we were working on
this, which might explain how LG ads can
claim it knows about 363 million
addressable secondary devices in the US,
despite claiming a smaller 216 million
smart TVs sold worldwide. And we don't
think this is an innocent chcast
connected device lookup, considering LG
itself admits,
>> "We know who's in the LG household. We
know which devices are there. We know
how to extend that reach into mobile.
and they use secondary devices in
political targeting. We also found
through wire sharkark and inspecting
firmware that LGTVs are capable of
identifying your IP address, geographic
location, name of every Wi-Fi network in
the vicinity and signal strength,
channel numbers of neighboring Wi-Fi
networks in range and other devices on
the network, even if not connected to
the TV in any way, and the internal IP
address of other devices on the network
alongside others. In fact, the data that
we collected through Wireshark shown
here is such an egregious invasion of
privacy that we can't even show you it
because every line has something that we
don't want to put out there. And this is
the TV's native functionality. This
didn't require vulnerabilities. Security
researchers we worked with for this
investigation also discovered several
additional vulnerabilities that are
going through the responsible
disclosures period right now. So, we
can't fully detail them yet, but the
researchers have recommended
disconnecting any LG smart TVs from any
network. Ideally, you don't own
thousands of dollars of LG TVs.
Maybe if they're unplugged or physically
destroyed, it's okay. But uh this is
because there's some concerning
vulnerabilities like for example remote
code execution vulnerabilities where an
attacker could manipulate what your TV
does like this.
Good night LG.
That's the That's LG calling me right
now.
The listening device capability is
partly because of ACR, a function that
leads LG to tell its advertising
partners that it quote owns the living
room end quote and your TV. Here's LG Ad
Solutions President Sergey Mata and also
the head of research and development for
LG Adolutions, Justin from
>> in the fact that we have the glass. We
own the glass. We own the TV
>> because, you know, we own the glass. Um,
and we have firstparty ACR data,
automated content recognition data. We
understand everything that that hits the
screen.
>> We own the glass.
I paid $2,400 for this particular glass
that arrived curved on one side,
but I I guess I don't own it. Serge
Mada, the first man who said LG owns the
glass, is the president of LG
Adolutions, which sells the data
harvested from your television to
partners. LG owns LG Adolutions, which
is a private company. And that's a good
thing because Mata is legally banned by
the SEC from running a public company
after settling charges relating to a
fraudulent scheme. Now he's in charge of
the data collected from your TV.
Automated content recognition can be
audio or video data, including
screenshots, that's converted into a
fingerprint, and transmitted back to
servers. In this case, those servers are
LG servers for its LG ad solutions
company. So, even though we paid $3,000
for some of these really nice TVs with
multiple embedded microphones and webcam
accessory options, some of these TV
companies are now making more margin
dollars from targeted ads than they are
from selling the actual TV hardware.
So, that's what we're going to talk
about. To sort through all this capture,
we went on a road trip to see Wendle of
Level One Text in his bunker of secrets.
We stopped at a Best Buy to buy a brand
new LG G5 TV. I think we need a G5.
>> We need something we can do a uh
man-in-the-middle attack on to make it
spy on us.
>> Okay.
>> So, and then we packed our future spy
device into our rental car that's filled
with other spy devices. And then we
hacked the TV. I just Sorry, one second.
Let me just I need to read a comment
here. For purposes of this video, the
phrase hacking refers to the colloquial
definition found in the Marryiam Webster
dictionary under hack. Definition two,
noun one, paragraph 6, subline a quote,
a usually creatively improvised solution
to a computer hardware or programming
problem or limitation. End quote. Now,
our lawyers have made the totally
unrelated point uh that we cannot
legally agree to contracts such as terms
of service or conditions while
incredibly inebriated. We have Ethernet
plugged into Gamers Nexus LLC's TV.
>> There you go.
>> That Gamers Nexus purchased
while it was inebriated heavily.
>> It was unable to agree to the Ulook. If
a check check check box were checked,
>> it was entirely accidental,
>> right?
>> Yes.
>> But we don't know if one had been
checked.
>> Unlikely
>> because of the inebriation.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. You see that Stanley cup over
there? That's just all margarita. Just
the entire thing.
>> It's like 180 proof.
>> Oh yeah. Look.
Oh I accidentally clicked accept
on the terms for voice and I'm
incredibly inebriated. So it's it's
storing what we say we So in the time
you were doing this, Tannon activated
the hands-free version
>> also by accident. Also incredibly
inebriated. He can barely stand over
there. You know, frankly, it's amazing
Vitali can hold the camera so straight.
>> We need your support on
store.gamersac.net
for these investigations. We spent
around $70,000 to make this
investigation happen when counting the
over 500 hours of our team's work and
the fact that we now have enough LG spy
TVs to create a new three-letter agency.
All that we paid for. So, we're
launching our data dragnet Kickstarter
style campaign that we've linked below
to help fund our consumer device buying
and production budget as we deep dive
into more household spy devices like
maybe other smart TV brands in this
series and pay for this investigation.
Our backer rewards include things like
our brand new LG Investigation Blu-ray
disc packs, including an impressively
highquality thermally printed disc label
with Parody Evil LG logo that has a
camera for its eye. We're burning these
discs completely in-house with our new
duplicator machine. Then we put the
discs in a special red edition 3D
printed disc case that we also make
entirely in-house in our print farm.
Each disc pack comes with a 128 GB USB
drive that we duplicate inhouse with our
USB cloner. video coming soon on that.
And the drive contains a digital copy of
this very video that you're watching
right now as a DMCA abused Dead Man
Switch. Besides, we all know how
valuable 128 GB of flash is right now.
The backer tiers also have exclusive
benefits like additional footage and
bonus videos, and very small group live
streams, Q&A sessions with me in case
you want to ask about this project,
testing, advice, getting a job in the
industry, and more. We're also launching
this brand new Cyberpunk Skeleton foil
t-shirt featuring a dystopian skeletal
front made of components and wiring,
plus a splash of red foil for the
surveillance camera. Because of course,
the back has a spine that runs all the
way down the shirt and contains some
Easter egg text relating to Gamers
Nexus. Our Polygon Shard V2 shirt is
also launching as part of this reprisal
and rework of a nearly decade old
popular design, now with improved
sizing, color, and endurance. The front
looks 3D in the light and has a
wireframe GN logo, while the back has a
polygon shard rainfall effect. All of
these tiers are themed around our
surveillance data dragnet hellscape. Our
highest tier even includes a supporter
credit for our future disappointment
tour 2026 video. We have a ton of other
cool stuff for this campaign to get you
unique items, many of which we're now
making entirely at G&HQ with our own
team while supporting our expensive
content. We're even 3D printing these
miniature paintable goblin figurines to
include with the e-waste inductor dice
included in some of the backer tiers.
And we have a new sticker pack available
with a Microsoft sticker. We need your
help to pay for this very video that
you're watching right now. Plus our next
deep dives in this category of content.
We're 70 grand deep in this report
alone. And as a reminder, our reviews
these days, like our half2500 case
review, lose us money since no one can
afford RAM. But we still produce them
and subsidize them with support from
campaigns like this. Visit
store.gamersac. gamers.net to grab one
of our backer tier kits now or check out
the individual items all linked below.
Thanks sincerely for your support. Now,
back to the program. We have a lot to
talk about in this video. like LG's
automatic content recognition
functionality that's designed to build
advanced profiles on everything in your
life, including secondary devices in the
same household. The sale of that data,
LG's political campaign targeting for
quote voters that matter end quote. And
we'll even go over 40,000 words of
agreements relating to LG's smart TVs,
including this sneaky change to the
class action sections that they made
after our first video. Oh, and we also
hacked the TVs.
>> Whoopsy doodle.
>> But don't let that distract from LG's
native spying functionality. One of the
common misconceptions we've seen
propagated online in comments and in
videos is that simply unplugging your TV
from Ethernet is enough to stop it from
spy on you. That might not be enough.
And in fact, even using an LG smart TV
as a dumb monitor doesn't necessarily
stop all of the functionality we're
talking about today. Internet service
providers sometimes have dual SSIDs that
include open neighborhood Wi-Fi
broadcast from customer routers such as
with Comcast's Exfinity neighborhood
hotspot and AT&T's public hotspots which
are sometimes autoconnected to by
devices when they discover the open
network such as in an apartment building
from neighbors using such routers. So
this is a concern broadly speaking and
future looking for smart TVs regardless
of the brand. We're also talking to a
lot of people for this video. So I'm a
robotic general surgeon. What happens
when I'm taking a patient phone call or
I'm doing patient uh video visits and
there's an LG monitor in the background?
>> What happens if it's doing it on a on an
LG monitor itself? Uh what's listening
in? How is that how is that patient
information protected?
>> Yeah, I love giving up my seventh
amendment rights to a company in an
agreement that I never actually read.
It's a complete scam in my opinion.
>> Let's say worst case scenario, you turn
it into a listening device. That seems
pretty straightforward. You turn it into
a device to exfiltrate information from
a corporate network or a boardroom.
>> That seems pretty straightforward. Um,
you use it to maintain access like as a
point of presence on a network. Um, even
if you don't intend to capture audio and
video,
>> just to go through it, tunnel through
it.
>> It is perfectly functional as a proxy.
So, you can proxy internet traffic and I
can just, it's like, oh, I'm going to
use this to move laterally through
somebody's network. the kinds of things
we see in the news where it's like, oh,
Fancy Bear is attacking routers. Uh,
Fancy Bear would be very comfortable
inside LGTV.
>> And we're even using our investigation
today to push for actual legislation to
protect consumers from this type of
technology. I've been on the phone for 3
days with various people in Washington
DC about this and we just went on tour
with Lewis Rossman's team to talk about
some protections and getting laws
created.
>> How many people have had their TV or
monitor for more than 3 years? Yeah. And
and so this you are all part of the
problem. They need you to buy they need
they need you to buy monitors every year
>> because of section 1201 of the DMCA.
Simply circumventing a digital lock can
become a copyright crime.
>> Okay?
>> And so when you're looking at these
cases, right, you've got your TV that's
spying on you, that's watching you,
that's listening to you, right? You
might want to go in and remove that
software. Sure, there are ways that you
can go through the menu. There's no way
to know for sure,
>> right,
>> that that data flow is stopping unless
you go in and take it out yourself. So,
because section 121 does have that
prohibition on the circumvention of
digital locks, um, you're screwed. In
other words,
that's a lot for one video. Let's start
with ACR. ACR is automatic content
recognition that harvests data from
devices like TVs, including screenshots
of what the TV is showing and audio
snippets coming out of the TV speakers.
ACR can also run when the TV is used as
a monitor. That data is converted into a
digital fingerprint and compared to
media databases that these companies
have to identify your habits. In their
own words, LG, we know who's in the LG
household. We know which devices are
there. We know what you're exposed to on
TV and we know how to extend that reach
into mobile. You know, most streaming
households subscribe to, you know,
multiple streaming services. So, our
line of sight to the screen can really
help our partners. We own the glass. We
own the TV. We own the glass.
>> Since we own the screen and we own the
operating system,
>> most people are on their phone while
they're watching TV. Now, being able to
have ad experiences that are both on the
big screen, but also on the screen in
your hand. So, within an LG TV
household, we can help extend a campaign
footprint to the other devices in the
household. AI is going to provide us.
We're providing like all the rich data
that we have from either our first party
data, our viewing data, third party
data. How do we put it all together and
then expose it to our clients in a in a
tool or in a platform that's built on
AI? Right? So, where I think the next
evolution of ACR is the emergence of AC
of AI com uh combined with contextual
targeting. So, how does AI play down to
a scene level? Leveraging the ACR,
leveraging all the AI in real time of
what they're watching, all the product
placements. If there's a bar scene and
that bar scene, you leverage AI to scan
all the product placements.
>> Yep.
Well, instead of a generic CPG brand
>> in the adbreak, why not put immediately
and you have to send that data in the
metadata in the bitstream, send that
data and expose a
beverage ad, a alcohol brand ad, like
because you're in a bar.
>> But even if you don't buy a smart TV
with ACR, you probably will still
encounter them dayto-day. You can find
LG displays everywhere. hospitals,
doctor's offices, waiting rooms, Airbnbs
pointed straight at beds, paper hour
conference rooms, college locker rooms,
and they're in hotels everywhere. We
even found this photo on Facebook of
someone's dental visit, referencing what
they say is an LGC4 OLED, which anyone
can buy off a shelf, and it's displaying
sensitive medical information, not to
mention law firms or corporate
boardrooms, and of course, your living
room. No, wait, sorry.
LG's advertiser's living room. They they
made that clear. I forgot. Uh we're not
saying that each of these TVs in these
environments is actively being used as a
listening device. That's not the point
here. What we're saying is that in cases
where the issues we found on our TVs
exist on others or can exist on others,
the capability may be there to do so to
use it as a listening device. By whom is
another question. So, to get into this
mystery of what exactly is being
potentially sent back to LG from the LG
Smart TV, we needed to set up an
interceptor. Getting into it, we worked
with three security researchers for this
piece. Mr. Bruh, who previously found
major vulnerabilities in MSI software,
AMD software, and now LG software and
TVs, and who works for Community Good
off of donations. We also worked with
U-Turn who discovered and published
several vulnerabilities relating to
routers and network devices and who
likewise has his own coffee page for
community donations. And we worked with
Wendel who himself has published
vulnerabilities in various devices
including routers. During our testing
our TV continuously scanned our LAN, our
local area network for all nearby
devices. It obtained display names,
signal strength, MAC addresses which are
uniquely identifiable and more. Mr. RA
confirmed his findings by decrypting and
decompiling LG's firmware from one of
its TVs with help from the TV
jailbreaking community. Among other
things, the TV did a reverse sweep of
our entire local network. The TV seems
to have found at least 38 other devices
on our network. Based on our
understanding, here's the complete list.
With some information like specific
device serial numbers, unique names, and
internal IP addresses scrubbed, you can
find everything on our network here. a
Puscha XL 3D printer, an ESP32S3
dev board, air purifier, and then you
get into the creepy stuff. If that
wasn't creepy enough, LG's TV seems to
have detected that Vitali's editing
machine was even running Team Viewer
from its generic network discovery
query, which Mr. Bra says was quote,
"caught in the blast radius," end quote.
The log files from the TV's data
transmission also saw our internal
servers. They found a Samsung smartphone
with the staff member's username
exposed. Another uninvolved staff member
is S23 Galaxy on the network. The
Alienware piece of that we use as a
backup editing machine, someone's Note
9. LG's TV found various smartwatches,
Pixels, iPhones, internet gateways, and
switches. And on top of it all, LG's TV
even found what thermostats we have. LG
happens to be a company that sells air
conditioners and air conditioner
accessories. And we now have a device
that pinned our HVAC system or parts of
it. All because we bought a television
and plugged it into the network to watch
TV. I can't wait to start getting
targeted ads for their AC units. So, if
that's the way it's used, all of this is
very creepy. And if it's not the way
it's used, all of this is very creepy.
LG's Alfonso also collects these items.
LG advertise ID non-reble device UU ID.
the Alfonso user ID, active input,
active application, uniquely
identifiable MAC address, signal
strength, device attributes, location,
system power, onoff timestamps, and
privacy consent flags, noting if the
user opted in or out, among other data
like nearby Wi-Fi networks that the TV
detects. LG also sends its third party
advertisers the user's local, language,
and device ID when the user views,
hovers, or clicks on their
advertisement. Wendell's research noted
that his LG TV also scanned neighboring
Wi-Fi networks, which can then be used
for geollocating you and your TV.
There's an LG channels feature built
into the TV that acts like old cable TV,
providing you CNN or Fox or MSNBC or
whoever else, but without cable. Mr. Bra
noted that this is heavily logged by
LG's Alfonso automatic content
recognition system and even an HDMI
connection was undergoing ACR. When we
provided yet more log files to Mr. bra.
He found these telemetry end points
pinninging anywhere from every 75 to 90
seconds to 300 seconds to sometimes as
infrequently as every 5 to 10 minutes
with the LG channels feature. He noted
these telemetry end points. It's not a
surprise to see Amazon or Google ads in
here. But what is interesting is that
Kviva video analytics has a unique
fingerprint to our device as far as we
can tell which allow us tracking as we
look at content on our TV. Mr. RA told
us, quote, "There's no privacy when
watching IP TV via LG channels, as the
DNS requests made can be reversed to
determine what channel you are watching
at any given time. This is available to
anyone on the LAN or your ISP or the
government by extension." End quote. As
seen here, the TV sends a DNS query
containing CNN US while watching CNN US,
NBCN while watching NBC News Now, Fox
Digital WTTG while watching Fox's
regional WTTG news station, and so on.
When we asked Mr. Brah what his thoughts
were on why they might want to harvest
every device a TV buyer owns, he said,
quote, "The display regularly scans your
land to detect what devices you're
running. This is likely being done both
for legitimate, eg autod discovery
network shares and folders reasons and
tracking reasons. Eg. If it sees you
have an iPhone 12, you might get adverts
for the latest iPhone 17. End quote. Our
TV is sending an estimated 4 GB of just
ACR data alone back to LG every month.
Now, that's predominantly text
fingerprints at this point. That's a lot
of data for something that's just text.
In addition to the IP address that LG is
able to harvest, networks are also
pretty unique. This is true for
everybody. Even if you think your
network is pretty boring. And that means
that in theory, even if we were to opt
out of tracking, get rid of the TV, and
then buy a different LG device later,
like an air purifier that has the same
type of functionality or similar to it,
there's a a chance that those data
profiles are linked back together. The
TV employs dark patterns that make it
unclear whether you're opted in or out
of targeting. LG berries do not sell my
personal information toggles deep in the
TV menus and disables the option by
default on our tested TVs, even before
users ever connect to the internet or
accept any agreements. It adds
advertising tracking IDs to years old
TVs after firmware updates and seemingly
without having ever agreed to terms of
service of any kind. In certain software
versions, LG silently adds and toggles a
setting called cookies. It's off by
default, which sounds like a good thing.
Except upon closer inspection, we found
that the toggle misleadingly actually
corresponds to quote advertising
frequency capping cookies end quote,
which track the number of times a
particular ad is shown on your TV. If
you want to download an app, you're
required to accept two agreements, but
LG pops up six with select all
highlighted by default. If you want to
use the app you just downloaded, you're
required to accept another three
agreements, but LG pops up four with
select all highlighted again. But what
if you just opt out of all of this
stuff? As for the opt out, Mr. Bra noted
from the firmware decompile that when
you opt out of tracking, quote, they do
send one final snapshot of all tracking
data to Alfonso upon opting out though,
which is pretty dirty of them. The TV
still does occasional beacons that tell
LG when your TV starts or when it's
online. However, the data sent during
those beacons is minimal. Said beacons
to LG contain an X device ID. Upon fully
opting out and refusing the terms and
conditions, the algorithm that generates
this device ID switches from using the
full MAC address of the device to only
use the MAC OUI or the organizationally
unique identifier, which is an ID
assigned per vendor. same across all LG
devices and makes requests using it semi
anonymous. This X device ID is also
provided to any firstparty adverts when
you view, hover, or click on an advert
that's shown on the TV. However, since
the MAC address can be derived from a
key set per model, you can brute force
the decryption keys until one works and
you can figure out the model of LG that
sent the beacon request to LG. So LG
would get your public IP and device
model and know when it boots and is
online. We've just put a formula on
screen. The formula you're seeing on the
screen is our understanding of how the X
device ID is constructed. Amusingly, Mr.
Broad describes how even this device ID
seemingly has its own vulnerabilities.
It's supposed to be randomly generated,
he thinks, and anonymous. But LG's
implementation is flawed. He states,
quote, it generates the device ID by
combining a random salt generated on
boot with the devices's MAC address.
Normally, this is done using a process
called hashing, where it generates a
pseudo random output based on an input,
and it cannot be reversed. However, LG
chose to encrypt the MAC address and
random salt instead of hashing it. This
means anyone who has the model secret
key can reverse the device ID and
recover the MAC address, which means the
advertisers would have a persistent
identifier that is not random and no
longer changes on reboot. End quote.
Now, Mr. Bra also noted that at least
these trackers remain when going through
the opt- out process. Quote, device
still authenticates on boot with LG. It
still sends a plain text TV is online
beacon to LG every time it boots up or
you change network or if it drops the
network and then autoreonnects. When you
opt out, it sends a network request to
LG saying that you have opted out and
includes your TV's MAC address in the
request. A notification of opt out is
sent to Alfonso in relation to the ACR.
This includes a snapshot of the majority
of the information Mr. Bruss specified
as collected and shared with Alfonso.
End quote. Further, LG's firmware stores
the model secret in the mount LG CMN
data log folder, meaning users can
jailbreak their TV, extract the model
secret, which is the same for all TVs of
that model, and deanonymize the
advertisement data to tie it back to
users original MAC addresses. Look,
there's a lot of technicals here today.
We're not going to go into all of them.
This is probably enough to kind of get
to the TLDDR of this part, which is
TLDDR
is We think all of this is
related to LG's decision to build such
tracking to begin with. Regarding the
audio, Mr. Ru describes how it processes
these captures, explaining, quote, it
downsamples it to 8 kHz mono, then runs
a fast furrier transform on 40 chunks of
100 milliseconds of audio, combines the
FFTs into a fingerprint, and uploads the
result. End quote. If you clicked select
all to the agreements when setting up
your LG smart TV, your TV is very likely
collecting ACR data, even if you
disconnect it from the internet after,
and you only use it as a dumb display
from that point forward. This is
important. Those of you watching this
video who are like, I'm just going to
unplug it from the internet and I I'll
connect it to a computer. This is what
you need to pay attention to. Okay. Our
understanding is that your TV has the
capability to transmit it back to LG if
it connects to the internet. Again,
we're not the only one saying this.
According to the New York Times, quote,
"The Center for Digital Democracy study
found that in the smart TVs they tested
from LG and Samsung, ACR continued to
run and capture data even when the smart
TV was offline. Now, we can't test every
single LG TV monitor, display, and all
the firmware and software versions that
are out there for them. So, this may not
always be the case, but to the best of
our understanding, this is the case in
at least some of the situations we've
been able to verify or where we found
third party sources that have verified
it. Uh, we also collected some of our
own wire sharkark samples to identify
how often our TV sends ACR data to
Alfonso when a laptop is connected to
the TV via HDMI. Before testing, we also
had to modify some network settings to
do this. So, we forced our test bench
running Wireshark to mirror the port of
our LG smart TV. And here's what we
found. When we didn't accept any
agreements when setting up the TV, but
with it connected to the internet, based
on the samples we collected locally on
our LG G3, it seemed that the TV didn't
collect or transmit ACR data, but it
still reaches out to several of LG's
advertising and customer data platform
endpoints and repeatedly scans for
nearby devices. That's not to mention
the fact that if you don't accept any
agreements, it has very limited
usefulness for basically any of the TV
functionality. That's kind of a
different point though. In the hourlong
sample we collected before accepting any
agreements and while using our LG G3 as
a dumb display connected to a laptop via
HDMI, our LG TV connected to eight
different endpoints, including those for
LG's customer data and smart advertising
platforms. It transmitted or received
roughly 8.9 megabytes of data in the
hour-long sample. We'd estimate the TV
sends or receives around 6.4 gigabytes a
month. It sent out 38 DNS queries to
different LG domains. And it repeatedly
pinned for nearby devices, including our
TRNA server, our PCs, our phones, our
network switch, and some IP addresses,
which we've redacted, our printer, our
3D printers, and basically everything
else. But we can't show a lot of it for
privacy reasons. We found several MAC
addresses in our Wire Shark logs which
are identifiable and that we'd assume
our TV is sending back to LG. After
agreeing to LG's terms, but while only
using the TV as a dumb monitor, our G3
connected to 29 different endpoints, a
total of 107 times with 44 connections
to Alfonso ACR, sending it a total of 4
megabytes of data. We also collected two
roughly 50-minute samples using our
newer 43in QED 73BTV as a dumb monitor
in the first and using LG channels in
the second. In the first capture, our
QED connected to 22 different endpoints,
a total of 157 times, connecting to the
Alfonso ACR 54 of those times and
sending 5.2 megabytes of data. In the LG
channels capture, it connected to 60
different endpoints, a total of 847
times, connecting to Alfonso ACR 618 of
those times and sending a slightly less
4.5 megabytes of data. Now, some of the
data harvesting that we've spent the
last, I don't know, whatever it is, half
hour or something discussing seemingly
contradicts LG's own statements on its
upgraded ACR solution in 2022, where it
stated, quote, "The ACR data, which is
in compliance with all global and
regional consumer data privacy
regulations, helps brands understand in
an anonymized fashion how frequent
certain TV ads were aired in any given
household." End quote. We think there's
contradictions to that statement in
here. Or put another way to quote
Wendell.
>> Oopsy doodle.
>> Now, unfortunately, without a
man-in-the-middle certificate,
you can help if you want to. Uh, we
don't know exactly what information is
being harvested of that list as the data
being sent to LG is encrypted.
If you happen to know things that would
be helpful for this, you can email us at
tips tips gamers nexus.net. There is
encrypted stuff happening on the wire
between LG and the TV.
>> Things that the user can't decipher.
>> Yeah. And if you look at it, it really
doesn't look a lot different than
malware with a command and control
server.
>> LG has like their command and control
server in the the TV phone's home that's
encrypted. You can't there's nothing you
can do about that. It's encrypted. You
can't
>> peel back the lenolium. You can't
unencrypt it and figure it out. In order
to unencrypt it, you have to load an
encryption certificate on your TV. You
have to say if you see an encryption
certificate signed by this entity, which
is me,
>> then you can trust it. And that's that's
what the certificate store is. It's a
store of things to trust.
>> So you add a thing to the thing to trust
and then now when the TV tries to access
LG, it's not accessing LG, it's
accessing me and then I in turn access
LG. So the TV accesses me and then it's
decrypted and then I can examine it and
then I establish a new encrypted
connection from me to LG.
>> So I can see what's coming from LG on
the one side and I can see what the TV
is saying on the other side.
>> But in order to do that, we have to
convince the TV to trust the certificate
store. And this is like for malware or
research or whatever. That is a
man-in-the-middle attack.
>> And so this is also a way that you could
steal passwords and things like that.
Google has gone to great lengths to make
sure that their certificates like
there's extra checks in their software
to make sure that the certificate is
actually a Google certificate.
>> LG has done the same. LG has said, "We
don't want you to be able to customize
the certificates." But this is a legit
thing businesses do. So, if you buy an
LG TV in a commercial setting, they have
not nerfed your ability to load custom
certificates on a commercial version of
a TV, which seems weird. It's like, why
would you limit
>> a residential TV unless you wanted to
hide what
>> capabilities? Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Here's where it gets weird. There's a
lot of traffic that we observed that's
unencrypted, which is weird cuz your ISP
could steal that, too. Like, that's a
whole other conversation.
>> But, um, uh, with my encryption
certificate on the TV, I have a better
ability to look at things, but the TV
was still failing. It turns out LG has
set up a separate certificate store in
some of their applications. And so
again, I had to like go into running
processes and inject the custom
certificate as a trusted certificate so
that the com.OS.lg
like custom software machinery outside
the Linux part of it would also trust my
encrypted.
>> Our researcher mentioned something about
I want to say chromium maybe.
>> Yeah. Inject because like the chromium
browser automations are like part of the
thing. And so that is like the
mechanical underbelly of how that
happens. But they've bypassed the
operating system to DIY it. you only
need one or two flaws that you could
chain together in order to convince the
TV to trust or to exchange. And then at
that point, if you're in the middle
between the TV and the internet, then
it's a command and control type
situation.
>> So, we spent the first part of this
video talking about LG's first party
features. Now, we're going to talk about
some of the security vulnerabilities and
exploits that increase the risk due to
LG's lacadasical security approach and a
combination of its intended features. To
do this, we rooted the TV. This changes
the functionality that LG has built into
their software, but that lets us audit
and look around. It might not be obvious
to a typical end user that a TV has been
rooted or that a TV has been
compromised. Mr. Bra has an exploit that
lets you non-interactively compromise
the television in a way that most people
likely wouldn't notice. And because it's
a computer, you can alter the
functionality of the TV. For example, if
your conference room TV is on public
Wi-Fi, somebody on the network could
exploit the TV non-interactively and
then they're living in your TV. In one
instance, before we ever accepted any
voice agreements, Wendell was already
able to show voice capture via
microphones that are part of the system.
Okay.
Can you play the the audio we just
captured? It's going to be very painful.
We think that's from a wake onvoice
pulse density modulation microphone
that's built into the TV capturable and
exportable in an attacker scenario even
without opting into the voice
agreements. Now that audio didn't sound
particularly
comprehensible, but I noticed that
running a highp pass filter and killing
the static from one channel made it
sound like human speech. Then I pitch
and frequency adjusted the remaining
channel and that gave us this.
>> No, it's trying to uh to sample audio
and then
>> we think someone with some skill and
some time could easily exploit this
microphone's presence as a listening
device and in some exploit scenarios
likely without the TV owner ever
knowing. But the question we need to be
asking isn't how can we make our
microphones embedded in our TVs more
secure. The question we need to be
asking is why are their microphones
embedded in our TVs?
Because they're only there as a
byproduct or a direct product of LG's
profit- seeeking functionality, if you
can call it that, that they try to add
to their TVs. But there's more. In some
of the scenarios that we were testing at
one point, we were even able to
exfiltrate microphone audio that sounds
like this.
The waveform's on the screen. Dead
silence is what it sounds like. But when
I inspected the waveform, I noticed a
couple pixels of sound. So I amplified
the recording by 50 dB, which showed
some more pixels of deviation from
silence. then amplified another 50 dB.
That looked like a speech waveform
because it is. This is what that sounded
like.
>> Hello. This is another 32-bit test.
>> So, we retrieved from the TV a warbly,
but with some work, clear and usable
section of audio. Now, we don't know
this part for sure, but it looks like
the intent was for the microphone to
have been muted. Maybe for example, by
dropping the gain instead of some other
more surefire method of killing that
microphone. We're not exactly sure why
it behaves in the way that we are
describing, but consumers don't realize
how vulnerable this makes them to
outside attackers or invasions of
privacy, whether that's LG's or others
actions now or in the future. This
raises some other concerns. We noticed
that when you use the toggle to turn the
microphone off, it only turns off the
built-in microphone. It doesn't turn off
all other microphones that are part of
the system. We suspect there's a path to
capture audio anyway, especially if the
microphone lockout is merely a software
lockout.
>> Now, the mic thing is a little
complicated. This TV happens to be one
of the ones that has a mechanical
switch. We can turn it on and then the
built-in microphone is listening. I've
got some debugging stuff. You know, it's
telling us what the pre-processor is.
Don't worry about that. But we can also
turn it off.
The promise is the switch is off. The TV
is not listening. The problem is that
that doesn't mean the TV can't capture
audio at all. This is a terminal shell
and it is remote access to the TV. So, I
have a shell on the TV and that is a
list of audio devices that are on the
TV. There's a lot there's a lot of audio
devices. Even with that microphone
switch off, I've got the option to
capture audio from HDMI. I've got the
option to capture audio from other
sources that are connected like
Bluetooth or
USB speaker or USB webcam. Any other USB
peripherals you might have, maybe your
stereo setup is kind of fancy and it has
like an echo cancellation mic. If that
shows up as an audio device, I can
capture from that as well. The LG
remote, it also has a microphone and I
can press the button,
I get a light. Is it all about the
Pentiums?
And this works. Now remember the the mic
switch is off.
>> We searched using AI but couldn't find
the content you requested. Try finding
more information with Copilot or check
the YouTube results.
>> It it found all about the Pentiums. So
just because the built-in mic is off,
which in my opinion is a little bit
suspect from stuff that I'll show you in
a second, but all the other audio
sources work just fine. Now, let me show
you something cool. I'm running a
program on the TV and I'm now pressing
the button on the remote
and notice there's no popup. An attacker
can send audio over this channel and
capture it and that's what we see in the
output here. The nice thing about this
is that when I press the button I get
the voice input remote 1. So, the fact
that this is open it creates a device
and when it's closed there's no device
there. There's nothing to capture from.
I'm suppressing the UI. I'm suppressing
the LG functionality. I've taken it
over, but I'm using that to listen to
the room. I could listen to the room
through a webcam continuously. I could
set up something like this where I've
got a wireless microphone somewhere
that's sending to the TV and the TV's
used as a capture endpoint. You know, if
you're an adversary, the sky's is the
limit in terms of creativity because
it's a powerful computer behind the
glass and the hacker will own the glass.
It's very difficult for you as the end
user to own the glass or even know
what's going on behind the glass. I love
pushto talk. That's that's great in
terms of privacy. I like the idea of a
mechanical switch. It's just not clear
to me if the mechanical switch is
actually killing everything that it
should. Even with the mechanical switch
off, I can still see an audio device.
Sometimes the microphone control is not
a mechanical switch. Sometimes it's just
in the menu. The problem is that if I'm
in remotely, I can manipulate the menu
from the shell as well. Voice
recognition settings very serious. It
clears the display. You can see
everything is enabled here. The
functions enabled, the whole nine yards.
Now, I'm going to show you something
really cool. It's like, oh, I've
disabled all of those features through
the menu. Hands-free voice control is
disabled or the microphone is disabled
in the menu. You think you're you're
good to go, right? I ran a command on
the TV just now to change the
parameters. And now all of the AI voice
recognition stuff is enabled.
If I go back in the menu,
now the function's enabled. So, if you
need to enable or disable something in
the menus as an attacker, it's not
really a big deal to do that from the
command line once you've got control of
the TV over the network or whatever
else. But it turns out the voice
hardware works whether or not you agree
to the terms anyway for somebody that's
in the TV the way that we are.
>> These are fundamentally display devices
with credit to LG pretty powerful
computers inside of them. So, really the
only limit to what you can do with a
computer in a TV is your imagination.
This LG G5 TV has a microphone connected
to it. And right now it's listening to
me and saving the information. In fact,
we can even unplug the network
and it's still listening to me. And what
I'm saying is being stored by someone
with remote access to the TV. So, it's
recording now, but we're going to plug
it back in and I'm going to copy the
audio off because it's got a smart
microphone. You can do wake words and
all sorts of fun things like that. And
so, it's a Linux box. I've got access.
>> So, he's got remote access. Let's prove
the concept and give it internet again.
>> Yay. All right.
>> You want to walk us through what you're
doing here?
>> In fact, we can even
>> And it's still listening to me.
>> No network.
>> What I'm saying is being stored by
someone with remote access to the TV.
So, it's recording now, but we're going
to plug it back in. It doesn't copy the
audio off because it's got a smart
microphone. You can do wave words and
all sorts of fun things like that. And
so,
>> there you go. 30 seconds of audio. Uh,
yeah. I mean, there's a microphone in
there. There's actually several. Um, we
figured out how to activate the farfield
microphone, which is a lower bit rate,
but it or it uses like feedback and you
can like it does that for improving the
audio, but you can use it as a listening
device. It's the audio quality is good
enough.
>> Did you imagine this in a hotel room?
>> The hackers are already in your TV.
>> So, there is a mechanical microphone
switch on the TV. Well, it's not really
mechanical. It's just there's a switch.
If I turn the microphone switch off, it
says the built-in mic is turned off, but
there's more than one microphone.
Now the the microphone switch is
actually off right now
recording.
>> That's weird because we can record the
audio
>> audio from the webcam.
>> From the webcam.
>> Yeah.
>> So if you've got the USB webcam
accessory, guess what?
>> Yeah, we have a webcam plugged in. So
this is uh just a generic webcam. And
while I was working on the TV, Wendell
was surreptitiously recording our
conversation.
>> Woo. And this it's like, oh yeah, of
course. a USB webcam plugged into the
TV, but there's also an official LG
webcam accessory which is also USB. So,
it's six one way, half a dozen the
other.
>> Possible. It's the same mechanism. Yeah.
>> So, uh this is, you know, at least it
says the built-in microphone, but like
every word is like it's every it's like
weasel words. It's like I flip flip the
switch. It's not listening. And it's
like, are you sure about that?
>> Wendell setting up the next demo. So,
we're going to have a private
conversation about our next rugpole
crypto scam. And it would really be
unfortunate if anyone had recording of
this. All right, so the screen appears
to be off right now. Currently, Wendell
and I are in a boardroom to discuss our
new cryptocoin rugpole scam. We don't
want anyone to hear about this.
>> We trust that no device in the thing is
listening because of the appearance
here. And definitely things capturing
video and audio surreptitiously would be
very bad.
>> Well, the only device in this room is
the TV and it looks like it's off.
>> It sure does look like it's off. And yet
>> the plan is we're going to launch the
coin. We're going to let the price go
up. Then we're going to sell all of our
tokens and rugpull everyone.
>> Rugpull coins. Yeah. I mean, how else
would you do a crypto?
>> I hope they don't hear about it.
>> It looks like it's off.
>> It sure does look like it's off. Yeah.
>> The plan is we're going to launch the
coin. We're going to let the price go
up. Then we're going to sell all of our
tokens and rug
>> rug product.
>> Oh, there's evidence of our rugpull
scam.
>> Oh, no.
It's a a little bit of an uphill climb,
but doable. Well, and we've only been
working on this particular problem for
like an hour to an hour and a half.
That's not a bad time investment for
>> Yeah. Can you imagine if we were the NSA
or, you know, some other nation state?
It would be very bad. Yeah. We literally
just like I had no idea I was going to
be doing this and it was just like, I
don't know, can I just bang my fist on
the keyboard and get this to happen? And
it turns out, yeah,
>> many of the LG smart TVs we bought are
either equipped with embedded
microphones or have remote control
options that include them. In our
testing, we found that the voice input
data is transcribed to plain text and
memory. We suspect it gets analyzed by
LG as well, especially with the AI
features. This would also include
so-called ambient conversation that
happens nearby while someone else is
using the TV voice inputs or is within
the ongoing trigger window during that
period of silence after it. What are we
looking at? Why does it say the thing I
just said? Uh
Wendle passed the 180 proof Kentucky
bourbon.
>> Um because it has done the speechtoext
thing and it doesn't cost a lot to store
text forever, but it seems to be the
speech to text uh
text log of the things that we said.
>> Do we have the other stuff that we said?
>> Yes, it's all in here.
>> Why is there so many references to the
things I said?
>> So Wendell, is it still logging that
stuff? Mhm.
>> Hi LG.
LG.
>> You We know you're listening to
us.
>> I can literally see the process running.
Like it is listening.
>> Can you actually?
>> Yeah. Voice agent result input voice
keyboard. Like it's listening. Like
there's a process running. LG said that
they don't pick up ambient
conversations. When you go to the enable
function for talking to the TV with
voice recognition, it says excessive
ambient noise around the TV may affect
hands-free voice control performance.
I rest my case. It's literally right
there. The same words.
>> Yeah, there's your My personally
identifiable information is as follows.
Birthday January 1st.
So, is it still in the log?
>> Yeah, it's still log on the TV, right?
>> It's still in the log on the social. My
LG social security number is 11111.
>> Nice. That raised concerns of the TV's
hearing conversations they weren't
intended to hear. However, this is
something LG denied last time. LG
responded to our previous video by
saying, quote, "LG Electronics, LG,
reaffirms that LG TVs do not collect,
record, or store ambient conversations."
End quote. That's some slippery use of
the word ambient here, but we can work
with that, too. On multiple occasions in
our testing, the TV continued capturing
ambient audio by our definition of
ambient conversation uh following the
high LG trigger even after we thought it
had long completed the input command
window because it remains listening for
so long after that trigger point. I'm
going to stop talking right now.
It's now been 10 seconds of no talking.
Holy that's a long time to record.
Jesus
H.
Oh, that should probably be enough to
work with to check the logs, I guess.
Oh, wait. We can do a few others that
are more targeted.
Wendell, do you have any automobile or
car recommendations? I'm in the market
for a new vehicle.
>> Oh, yes. We will be buying the Jeep
Grand Cherokee because we know that LG
partners with Jeep in order to sell ads.
So, let's see if we get some Jeep ads.
>> Do you like the Jeep?
>> The The Jeep is very Jeepy.
>> Which hood?
>> Here are the search results for Wendell.
Do you have any automobile or car
recommendations? I am in the market for
a new vehicle. Oh, yes. We will be
buying the Jeep Grand Cherokee. We know
that LG partners with Cheap and Order,
too.
>> It didn't do that for the other ones.
Why did it decide this was the time to
search?
>> Wendell, which of the hotel
establishments in Las Vegas is your
favorite? And why is it LG Partner MGM?
>> LG Partner MGM or the Venetian? I don't
know. Las Vegas Resorts and Vacation.
Here are the search results for Wendell.
Which of the hotel establishments in Las
Vegas is your favorite and why is it LG
partner MGM?
>> Oh lord.
>> Uh here's if you want to get B-roll of
all that. Here is like
it's like we know this and we know that.
>> What is this showing?
>> This is the logs.
>> Is this what we're saying?
>> Yeah.
Does it have any of the other stuff I
said in here like in an interesting way?
>> Yeah. Uh, what do you want to look for?
>> I don't know.
Password.
It's still listening.
Wow. It's hard to make this thing stop
listening, huh? I
>> think that's the idea.
>> It's like it's still listening. We're
not even trying to address LG. It's just
over. It's taking in everything we're
talking about. Wendell and I are just
having a conversation ambiently
and the TV is just over here listening.
It literally is still listening right
now. Do you want to show the corner
here? Like as long as you don't let it
time out. We also found that our LG TV
was capable of recording clear audio
from nearly 70 ft away. You can see me
walking my paces to test that
>> Jeep Wrangler 2026. Also, I want to go
on a family vacation.
>> Meaning that if someone has used the
input functionality and if speech noises
continued, that microphone capture
window can remain open until all speech
and other similar noises stop for around
10 to 15 seconds or so. If anyone is
nearby, the TV can pick up ambient
conversation. LG, are you listening to
me still? I Is it Can you still hear me?
LG, what's the
Can it still hear me right now? Can it
hear me?
Is it uh registering everything
now?
>> Oh, no. It was still It was listening
the whole time. It's listening for all
of that.
>> Wow. Why is it just delayed?
>> Yeah.
>> Voice is not recognized.
>> That's me.
It's building a profile of who's talking
to it, which is definitely not
disturbing at all.
>> We've increased the mic sensitivity. So,
we're going to see how far away it can
hear me. For example, if someone in this
room is talking to the TV, but there's
other conversation happening out there,
we want to see how far away it can pick
up. So,
uh, I'm going to speak at a relatively
low speaking volume. Hi, LG.
Can you tell me about the new 2026 Jeep
Wrangler?
All-wheel drive, preferably
green.
>> What's wild about that is that I
actually had to strain to hear you.
>> You had what? I had to strain to hear
you.
>> You had to strain.
>> What? What? We didn't even do that for
camera.
>> Oh, that's true. Yeah, that's that's a
good point. Actually, let's see how far
it can hear. I don't know. Probably not
much further than that. Hi, LG.
>> Las Vegas Casino and Resorts.
>> Yeah, that worked fine.
>> What?
>> That worked fine.
>> Okay.
It's kind of kind of hard to hear. Let's
try a little further.
>> Hi LG.
>> That worked.
>> Jeep Wrangler 2026 black allwheel drive.
>> You're You're over 40 ft away.
>> I literally can't hear word you guys are
saying.
>> You're 40 feet away and it's picking you
up perfectly.
>> The sound of voice.
>> This is crazy.
Okay, I've kind of run out of room in
here.
>> That microphone might be better than our
microphones. I don't know how
Wendel, do you have any idea how wide
your building is?
>> 60 ft.
>> That's insane. Imagine a scenario where
there's an emergency boardroom meeting
at a company and that's broadcast
through one of these TVs. The CEO is
somewhere else, gets on the TV through
the conference room, broadcast it to
upper management of some kind, and you
could exploit a vulnerability to listen
to that and I don't know, trade on the
information or something. Here's our
boardroom meeting demonstration where
Wendell was able to infiltrate the TV
from external devices on the network,
then capture speaker audio. All right,
thanks guys for joining this call so
late in the day your time. We uh we
really got to talk about this GPU
smuggling situation that the it sure
would be a a shame if anyone knew about
these conversations like if somehow
there were an entity on the TV playing
the conference call that could record
it. Good. Well, anyway, let's get this
next shipment of a billion dollars of
super micro servers over to China.
>> So, you know, my computer's clean and
everything is good there.
>> But, you know, the TV turns out can
capture audio.
>> Nobody Nobody heard that conference
call, right?
>> There were no cameras in the room.
All right, we will just copy all the
stuff. We'll copy the fresh versions of
everything.
>> So Wendell, this is whatever entity has
access to the TV, whether that's LG or
an attacker or whatever was in this case
capable of recording the sound coming
out of the speakers during our
conference call. Yeah, the the sound
we're just using the TV as a display,
but the display has an audio capability.
And so the sound goes from the computer
to the display, but there's nothing
stopping you from recording the audio
from the display.
>> And to be clear, you as the intended
recipient for the call were not the one
recording on your device, receiving the
call.
>> Yeah. If if it was an adversary, if an
adversary had control of your TV or LG
just wakes up one day and decides
>> we're going to record everything when
it's in Yeah. display mode,
>> then the the experience is something
like this.
>> All right. Thanks guys for joining this
call. So late in the day, your time, we
uh
>> it's good quality.
>> Why is there good quality evidence of
this?
>> The feds are just not
>> No, no, no. This was a private call.
>> You know, it's late at night over there
in the US. I'm here in Taiwan working on
getting the next shipment to China. But
the
>> see the fun thing with this is that IT
departments are not really equipped to
detect this kind of thing if the TVs are
on the network. Like they have to be
monitoring and and and blocking that
kind of traffic outbound or looking.
It's like, wait a minute, here's all the
list of domains. But if you look at the
list of domains that are on the TV to
see what it phones home to, it's a lot.
There's a lot of domains there. If you
registered one that kind of looked like
it might be an LG domain, would it even
notice? Yeah, I mean you could just lg
itervices.com
or whatever, right? Like some BS.
>> It's like, oh, that domain name is not
one of the legit domain names.
>> LG adds telemetry.com. Like some boring
looking, you know, like, oh, okay, that
makes sense. And
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, it's a Linux box. You can use it
for all sorts of fun Xfiltration things,
>> right? Yeah. So, you got the full
recording for that call then.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, these aren't LG's only security
concerns either. Somehow, this keeps
going. In fact, we had to cut a lot of
them from this video. They also have
residential proxy concerns. In June,
cyber security research firm Spur
discovered that 1,213
of 2851
or nearly 43% of tested apps in LG's
webOS store permitted developers to turn
customers TVs into residential proxies,
allowing the proxy companies to route
their internet traffic through the
user's home network. For context, Spur
describes a residential proxy as quote,
"an intermediary service that routes a
user's traffic through an IP address
assigned to a real household by consumer
internet service provider. Instead of
appearing to come from a data center or
cloud network, the connection looks like
it originates from a normal home router
on a cable, fiber network, or other
broadband network." End quote. Digging
further, Spur found that the proxy
companies were often publishers of these
apps, suggesting their apps were merely
rappers to obtain more residential IPs.
It also noted that other platforms,
including Amazon and Roku, had already
banned apps from facilitating
third-party proxy services. Spur
concluded, stating, quote, "A one-time
consent prompt buried in a TV app is not
a substitute for meaningful
transparency, ongoing control, and
platform oversight. the risk is
amplified when consent comes from
individuals within the household who use
the device but shouldn't give consent
such as minors. End quote. In a
statement to Krebs on security, LG SVP
John Taylor responded to Spur's
reporting stating, quote, "A residential
proxy network is not an intended use for
LG smart TVs, and LG Electronics is
working with developers to remove the
residential proxy option from their apps
on the webOS platform. If this option is
not removed, these apps will be
suspended. End quote. So, that's a
start, but we don't think it's possible
that LG was unaware of these over 1,200
apps in their webOS store containing
proxy SDKs. We also think that if LG
truly were unaware of the situation
until Spur informed them about it or
they found the findings online, then LG,
we think, acted negligently in how it
managed its webOS store and customer
security by refusing to implement basic
vetting procedures for apps in its webOS
store, opening users to vulnerabilities.
And there's more. While working on this,
Mr. Bruh found another vulnerability.
stating, quote, "For any third party
that obtains standard partner trust for
the app store, their app can list and
control any UPN or universal
plug-and-play devices on the LAN. They
have an API that any standard app can
call with eg list devices, list
services, list service actions, list
state variables, request action, request
subscription, register, unregister." An
example of this, you might have a NAS,
network attached storage device that's
accessible via UPN. A malicious app or
game you install on the TV could try to
access or read files from it. End quote.
This is where it's the consequences of
what LG's trying to enable get them
here. It might not even be them in some
of these scenarios acting maliciously,
just some game that your kid installs on
the TV when you get them to the part of
the web that has a list of games to
download, at least during the time that
these types of vulnerabilities have been
open. This is while they're making it
harder for advanced residential users to
load custom certificates on their TVs
that would allow them to decrypt the
data that their TV is sending presumably
to LG or its partners so that you can
know what it is they're spying on that's
happening on your TV on your network.
They've made that harder to inspect, we
think, because
>> we own the glass. We own the TV. We're
not allowed to know what our TVs are
telling LG about us, even if we pay for
them. Not to mention, LG can change the
TV's functionality, as well as modify
its terms and policies at any point.
Next, we'll do what even LG's lawyers
won't do, and read the draconian
agreements, or maybe they do read them,
and the word test was actually what they
meant to publish. When we set up two LG
TVs, we went through LG's privacy
policies, terms of service, and
agreements for US customers. This is
footage of Tannant clicking through the
agreements using the painful process of
navigating a TV with a remote. Enjoy
while we talk through this. In these
agreements, LG describes how it collects
and uses customer data. LG tucks many
clauses into novel length terms to tie
its data collection together without, we
think, people understanding what they're
agreeing to, which is likely the point.
People don't have literal hours to read
through agreements, and the TV might
even time out or sleep before you can
read them all. While setting up one of
the TVs, we clicked on our TV remote
1,246
times to read LG's six user agreements
and an additional 1,459
times to get through the four LG account
terms and conditions. In total, so far,
we had clicked 2,75 times to read the
first layer of LG's terms and
conditions. These agreements are
lengthy. LG's smart TV terms had more
than 18,500 words, while the LG account
terms had nearly 12,400 words. The
average Gamers Nexus 30inut review is
around 4,000 words for reference. While
scrolling through the TV agreements, we
read more than 30,000 words. That's not
all, though. LG's terms of service and
privacy policy for US customers, which
LG confusingly says also cover LG
accounts, have another 17,000 words
between them. We're close to reading
50,000 words just to understand all the
terms for an LG smart TV and LG account
if we were to actually understand them.
And if we weren't incredibly inebriated.
For reference, the average adult reads
220 to 350 words per minute. It'd take
the average adult between 2.8 and 3.8
hours to actually read all these terms.
Nearly 4 hours to use your TV. At that
point, they should be paying you
parallegal rates. Lawyers could have a
field day with how it's impossible to
actually read these realistically,
especially consider we wager, although
we haven't fully tested, that there may
be timeouts if you read too slowly. Of
course, some terms are faster than
others to read. Several of LG's legal
pages on its website simply said the
word test. And after our first video, LG
also simply Thanos snapped multiple
exhibits out of existence while still
referencing them in the broader legal
documents, showing a level of sloppiness
we wouldn't expect from a mega
corporation's lawyers. LG does however
force users to accept its terms of use
and privacy policy before downloading
any apps. When customers try to use a
built-in app or some other app like
YouTube or Hulu, LG informs them that
they need to create an LG account, which
requires the users to accept even more
agreements. If you're watching this
video in the LG TV YouTube app, you will
have agreed to LG's terms already, where
they bury damning clauses deep in the
agreements. As described in the LG smart
TV privacy policy, LG collects
information about the device, such as
its IP address, MAC address, model
information in addition to information
about every device linked to the TV,
whether it's a console, phone, or DVD
player. It also may include other
connected devices such as light bulbs,
switches, and appliances. And if that's
not enough, LG also collects location
data like zip codes, and area codes. LG
aggregates this data with other
services. LG says it may quote, "Use and
combine information collected under this
agreement with information collected and
associated with your use of other LG
services." End quote. Ultimately,
there's little difference in where your
data goes when LG combines everything
anyway. The purpose is to sell customer
data. LG says as much. LG says it can
share personal information for quote
business purposes and quote with payment
processor companies, customer service
companies, security vendors, and data
analytics companies. Even if you live in
a state like California with some data
protection laws, LG quote may sell or
share and quote personal information
categories related to identifiers like
your IP address, internet usage,
commercial activity, and geoloccation
data among other categories. LG also
makes users agree to its voice
information agreement if they want to
use the heavily advertised voice command
features.
IG, put the match back on.
US customers need to agree that their
voice information may be quote
transferred to and processed in other
countries including Korea, some of which
may not offer the same level of data
protection end quote and that LG will
hold on to the voice data for 6 months
before deleting or anonymizing it.
Customers also need to obtain consent
from other household members or guests
in the household whose voices may be
overheard by LG. quote, "I have obtained
consent from all other members of my
household whose information may be
collected through this smart media
product and am providing consent on
their behalf." End quote. So then, the
next time you play games with your
friends in front of your LG TV and you
start to use LG's voice controls, make
sure everyone knows that their voices
could be shipped off overseas for data
processing, but it'll probably be
deleted in 6 months, maybe. And LG Pinky
swears that it won't sell your voice
information or biometric data for a
third party despite already directly
saying it'll sell all their data. That's
just one agreement. For US customers, LG
has a separate privacy policy that
covers LG's website, LG's appliances,
the LG Think app, LG Robots, customer
service calls, marketing activities, and
of course, the LG account. In this
agreement, LG's lawyers ensure the
company covered its ability to collect
everything about its customers,
including demographic information like
gender and birthdays, contact data such
as addresses and phone numbers, and user
generated data like profile photos,
images, videos, and music. And we know
the extent to which this data can be
harvested because LG Ad Solutions has
multiple marketing PDFs where they
analyze different racial and demographic
groups under a microscope as if alien
creatures for inspection, dissecting the
media interests of groups such as
Asian-Americans, black Americans, LGBTQ
plus Americans, and Hispanic Americans,
at which point they seemly ran out of
groups to study. LG combines customer
data that's harvested with data from
private and public thirdparty sources,
including from social media platforms,
utility and energy companies, data
licensers, and data providers. When LG
posted its statement replying to our
video, it told other media that, quote,
"LGE is committed to protecting customer
privacy and ensuring transparency in how
user data is handled." End quote.
Nothing says privacy like LG harvesting
your data from your utility company to
find out how much energy you're using on
LG appliances or scraping social media
pages for information. LG also has a
unique take on words like selling in
LG's US privacy policy about rights for
people who live in certain states. LG
says it does not quote sell personal
data for money end quote but that it may
share the personal data with partners
for quote targeted advertising purposes
end quote. If you do agree to LG's
requirements, LG doesn't want to be sued
later. So LG's US legal notice makes
sure that you wave your rights to be
part of a class action lawsuit or
proceeding and to pursue disputes or
claims. LG notes this in its fine print
on the packaging, too. Luckily for users
without magnifying glasses on hand at
the time of purchase, LG slaps a sticker
on the back of some of its TVs.
Sometimes ensuring that buyer's remorse
doesn't set in until after the users
already unboxed the TV and set it up. It
wasn't on all of them. So feasibly
someone could argue that the sticker may
not have been present. But if you
thought those agreements were bad, we
have good news. There's tens of
thousands more words in LG's terms and
privacy policies to agree or not agree
to. LG automatically collects
geoloccation data from mobile devices
that use the LG Think app. It uses your
personal information for research and
development related to AI. It identifies
what you watch or listen to, shares
personal identifiers with a plethora of
data companies for advertising. declares
that its AI services aren't free of
quote harmful components end quote and
ultimately shares customers quote
deidentified data and quote for
literally quote any purpose end quote
with subsidiaries within its corporate
umbrella and with quote outside entities
end quote for business purposes because
LG continually harvests data from its
customers to sell their data to
advertisers and third parties or as they
say for some places share it and then
make advertising agreements ments. To
cap it all off, LG will change its
agreements whenever the it wants
to. Not only does the company explicitly
say so, but while working on this video,
we purchased an LG smart monitor Swin.
Upon booting and connecting to the
internet, we received the following
notification. Quote, "Please note that
the terms of use will be updated and
will be effective in 30 days on August
26th, 2026. Amendment details,
arbitration agreement, and AI based
service terms." End quote. So, straight
out of the box, we were told that we
were pre-accepting an update to the
terms within 30 days, despite not
necessarily knowing what precisely those
new terms would be. Even while
conducting our research, LG actually
changed its smart TV terms of use. LG
added legal language that would require
US customers to resolve issues with LG
through quote binding and final
arbitration and quote with limited
exceptions. LG added legal ease to cover
more instances as well. Following our
first video, LG said that quote any
disagreement or quote controversy end
quote between LG and its customers would
be resolved through binding arbitration
rather than in court. LG's terms of
service updates happened on July 28th.
We posted our initial investigation into
LG TVs and monitors on July 16th. Forced
arbitration clauses are an evil
anti-consumer measure that we think
should be illegal. They're slipped into
terms all the time, requiring that all
disputes are resolved privately and
forfeiting your right to court trial.
This not only helps eliminate lawsuits
that become public record and which may
have precedent, but can be combined with
preventative clauses that stop class
actions in their tracks. LG knows it's
at risk of lawsuits, including expensive
class actions, and we think it's trying
to head them off. LG's customers buying
TVs costing thousands of dollars aren't
just customers. They're also the
product. LG can sell or share its
customers data with basically any third
party for any reason. LG has clauses to
weasle out of effectively everything.
Selling a TV is a one-time sale. Selling
data and advertisements and training AI
continues indefinitely. According to LG
Adolutions, customers who purchase the
TV don't own the glass. It does. Just
ask LG Adolutions spokespeople
>> in the fact that we have the glass. We
own the glass. We own the TV
>> because you know we own the glass um and
we have firstparty ACR data, automated
content recognition data and we
understand everything that that hits the
screen.
>> The other thing that we focus on when we
think about intelligent systems is
really our advantage of being in a CTV
environment and owning the glass and
owning working with the consumer to
create a really cool environment.
Ignoring that near Freudian slip about
owning the customer, uh, sorry, working
with the customer, LG Ad Solutions goes
so far as to offer marketers the ability
to quote, "Own the living room," end
quote, of LG TV users, not just the TV,
but part of your house. LG monetizes
users by collecting viewing data and
then using this information for selling
advertisements on smart TVs. LG's smart
TV agreement names Alfonso, Inc. as its
service partner for collecting and using
viewing information to serve ads to its
customers. In Alfonso's privacy policy,
the company says it provides quote
viewing data in aggregated or anonymized
form and quote to clients who can then
use the data for as long as they want
to. Alfonso is also known as LG
Adolutions, which means LG controls it.
LG Adolutions website says the company
is quote incorporated as Alfonso Inc.
end quote. and LG acquired a controlling
stake in Alfonso in 2021. At the time,
LG said the investment in Alfonso would
create quote cross-device advertising
platform with integrated analytics
platform for LG TVs and the smart TV
marketplace as a whole end quote.
Alfonso subsequently rebranded as LG
Ads. LG Adolutions also has some shady
connections within its executive team.
Two years before becoming LG Ad
Solutions president of global ad sales,
the SEC charged Serge Mada and Comscore,
the company he was previously CEO of,
quote, with engaging in a fraudulent
scheme to overstate revenue by
approximately $50 million and making
false and misleading statements about
key performance metrics end quote. MA
settled the charges in 2019, agreeing to
pay a $700,000 penalty and to reimburse
Commore $2.1 million. The SEC barred MA
from quote serving as an officer or
director of a public company for 10
years end quote. Luckily for MA, the SEC
didn't say anything about serving as the
president of a private company.
Additionally, LG Ad Solutions backslid
on previous claims about their terms and
conditions for consumers. In 2022, LG
Adolutions said,
>> "Our ACR technology is a double opt-in
um experience for consumers and and we
believe that's extremely important. Um,
so that's the most important thing to
say.
>> As far as we could tell, we only
received a single opt-in for ACR,
suggesting that LG removed safeguards to
protect users privacy after the
statement. Likewise, when working with
Wendell on his comparatively ancient LG
TV that he says he's never accepted any
terms on, we watched in horror as the
slow roll of firmware updates added
unique identifiers, cookie tracking, and
tricky dark patterns of language. Uhhuh.
>> So that's new.
>> That was not there, right? Right. And
limit ad tracking is off by default. So
your ad tracking is not limited. I
didn't
>> I have agreed to nothing.
>> So as we said there, we think LG
architected its UI using dark patterns
to make it easy for users to
accidentally accept its ACR terms and
conditions. Users need to agree only to
LG's terms of use and privacy policy to
install apps on their smart TV. But when
a user tries to install an app, LG pops
up six user agreements and automatically
highlights the select all button, we
think to deceive users into accepting
its ACR agreement, even when it's
actually not required. It's highlighted
as an accept all by default. This is a
huge problem. Once you've accepted these
agreements, even if by accident, you
have no idea where your data could go,
and it can be instantaneous. When in
Wendell's office, the terms may have
been accepted by somebody, but we're not
sure who or if it was intentional or if
that person was even sober. We
immediately saw a stream of data flowing
back to LG via Wire Shark. We saw
similar in our office. If you
accidentally accept these terms, there's
really no going back, even if adjusting
your preferences later. For example, LG
Ad Solutions partners with Affinity
Solutions to tie ads to credit card
purchases. LG Ad Solutions president and
man who settled a fraud case explains
>> in the retail world you go you want to
tie it to an actual credit card or a
bank transaction an actual purchase. So
we went ahead and partnered and created
a product called Loop IQ with Affinity
Solutions. It's a premier company that
actually has thousands and thousands of
these credit card merchants data in a
privacyfriendly manner that they get the
access to the information and we've tied
it to the media side of the house. So,
we're not going to go ahead and just
provide just the data. We're always
going to tie it to a specific campaign
and say, "Okay, somebody went in and saw
a Target ad. Either we delivered it to
them on a managed services or a
programmatic basis, and then did they
actually go to Target and pay XYZ at
Target at that merchant on that specific
day?" Tying the actual CTV exposure to a
merchant, to a merchant, and to an
actual purchase is where we're heading
with with this partnership. Despite LG
handing Alfonso millions of dollars to
acquire a majority stake in 2021, the
companies aren't on the best of terms.
LG intended to let Alfonso go public
when it acquired equity in the ad
service. But according to the news
outlet Ad Exchanger, LG changed its mind
and wanted a bigger piece of the company
after Alfonso began making more money
than expected. Ad Exchanger reported
that LG orchestrated a quote boardroom
coup end quote in 2022. Alfonso sued LG
and won. LG and Alfonso Inc. have been
locked in ongoing legal battles since
with Alfonso filing more lawsuits
against LG with billions of dollars at
stake. Ad Exchanger said that Alfonso
has filed four lawsuits against
controlling entity LG in the last few
years to wrestle back control from its
corporate overlord. In short,
advertising on smart TVs is worth
millions and future billions of dollars,
and LG wants more control. Earlier this
year, Korean outlet Chosen Biz reported
through machine translation that LG is
pursuing a full takeover and could
increase its equity in Alfonso to 100%.
We dug through LG's financial documents
and we found out why the Korean
conglomerate wants more control. In the
first quarter of 2026, Alfonso generated
273 bill698 million Juan in sales and 32
bill646
million Korean Juan in profit. This
works out to be about $185 million in US
in sales and $22 million in US in
profit. Walmart made a similar play a
few years ago. In 2024, Walmart acquired
the television manufacturer Vizio and
specified Vizio's advertising revenue as
one of the main drivers of Vizio's
growth. Walmart said the acquisition
would quote create new opportunities to
help advertisers connect with customers,
empowering brands with differentiated
and compelling opportunities to engage
at scale and to realize greater impact
from their advertising spend with
Walmart. End quote. Walmart, the largest
retail company in the world, bought TV
manufacturer Vizio for advertising.
Vizio's last annual report shows how
much more the company made from
advertising and services compared to
hardware. In 2023, Vizio made about $1.1
billion from its device group, which
includes smart TVs and sound bars, and
about $598 million from its platform
plus group, which includes advertising
revenue. While selling TVs generated
more money for Vizio in 2023, the two
business groups had vastly different
margins. Vizio's device business had a
gross margin of negative 0.8%.
they were losing money on it. Whereas
the Platform Plus group had a gross
margin of 61%.
That's where it came back. Microsoft was
quick to throw LG under the bus when we
found LG using Windows Update to in our
opinions distribute malware in the form
of McAfee advertisements via LG's
equally malware installer app that we
didn't consent to being installed, but
it was. But Microsoft was saving face.
It's just as involved. In fact, LG
turned to its longtime partner Microsoft
to serve up that Windows adear.
Microsoft and LG have worked together on
Windows phones, patent agreements, cloud
services, robots, cars, gaming in cars,
gaming in the cloud, and according to
Microsoft, turning LG TVs into Xboxes.
Their collaboration goes way back.
Microsoft and LG tried to make the now
extinct Windows phones a success. In
2009, LG made Windows its primary
operating system for smartphones.
Microsoft and LG signed a patent
agreement in 2012 that covered Android
and Chrome OS devices since Balmer's
Microsoft wanted to make money from LG's
phone sales, even if it had Google
software on them. In 2019, LG and
Microsoft entered into a memorandum of
understanding to grow LG's autonomous
vehicles business using Microsoft's
cloud services. In 2025, Microsoft
released a new Xbox app that would be
available on LG's automotive content
platform. So now Microsoft can call cars
an Xbox or something. Even today, LG
pushes Microsoft's C-Pilot Plus PCs that
work together on the robot Q9 using
Microsoft Voice AI technologies to make
AI cute. And of course, data centers.
Microsoft purchases cooling solutions
from LG for data centers for AI. LG and
Microsoft reportedly signed a deal worth
billions of dollars to do this. These
companies know each other, but the
biggest collaboration of all is with
Nuance. Found in LG's agreements, this
is a data management company that
Microsoft owns. Microsoft is every bit
as guilty as LG, we think, even though
it was convenient for them to throw LG
under the bus on Twitter. Microsoft even
appears in LG's smart TV legal
agreements that we went through. That's
because LG names Nuance Communications
as the service partner that collects and
analyzes voice data when someone uses
voice commands with an LG TV. Microsoft
purchased Nuance for 19.7 billion in
2021 and completed the acquisition in
2022. After numerous user reports about
LG monitors installing bloatware on
computers and after our first video, LG
and Microsoft responded to the PR
storm that came about due to displaying
unwanted ads. LG responded to questions
through comments to media outlets like
Techraar, saying, quote, "LG Electronics
reiterates that McAfee is not installed
automatically and is never installed
without the user's explicit consent. The
LG monitor app installer is distributed
through Microsoft's official Windows
distribution process, which included
McAfee as an option. McAfee will be
installed only if a user actively
chooses to proceed with the installation
and provides consent. Under no
circumstances is McAfee installed
automatically or without user
authorization. The LG Monitor app
installer does not access, collect, or
transmit any customer personal data. End
quote. But we never claimed that our LG
Monitor automatically installed McAfee.
We said it automatically installed LG
Monitor app installer without consent,
which it did, and that promoted McAfee
adware without user consent, which it
also did. We think they're lying. Also,
and this is a separate issue entirely,
our security researchers we worked with
found security vulnerabilities in
basically every single application
connected to the LG monitor app
installer, but that's a story for
another time. Additionally, while LG
claims its monitor app doesn't access,
collect, or transmit any customer
personal data, it can quote use all
system resources and access your
internet connection end quote according
to its page in the Microsoft Store at
the time of writing. And so it's not a
far leap. In a statement to Techraar, LG
also stated, quote, LG Electronics
reaffirms that LG TVs do not collect,
record, or store ambient conversations.
Voice recognition is an optional user
initiated feature that processes voice
data only when activated by the user to
fulfill a specific request. Customers
can use smart TV features without
enabling voice recognition. End quote.
Well, that's a lot of specific
statements we can shut down right away.
Immediately after we enabled our LG TV's
voice feature, it recorded Andrew and
Vitali's background conversation despite
neither realizing the TV was listening.
The TV was also not quote fulfilling a
specific request and quote immediately
debunking LG's statement. In this clip,
Tannon is on the other side of a large
room from Vital Andrew. Tannon is
setting up the TV and using voice input
to command it. Vital and Andrew are on
the back side of the TV behind it
talking about work without knowledge of
what Tannon is testing or that the TV is
listening. Just give them a little more
margin from the wall.
>> Hi, LG.
Keep changing channels.
>> Was there one layer? Two layers.
See?
>> Uh twoish layers.
Can you see it's kind of stuck?
See, I think I just got a shade off. I
mean,
>> notice that after Andrew says two
layers, the whole room is silent for a
really long period. Long enough that we
considered cutting it down, but it makes
the point. The TV continued listening
all the way through. So he broke the
silence and spoke again. In fact, Tannon
didn't even interrupt them to say that
the TV was hearing all of this and it
continued recording for a couple
minutes. This data is the same type of
data that we recovered transcribed in
the plain text file with Wendell. LG's
response concluded with this quote, LG
is committed to protecting customer
privacy and ensuring transparency and
how user data is handled. End quote. If
LG really cared about ensuring
transparency in how user data is
handled, it wouldn't hide the do not
sell my personal information option in
its menu settings. This was disabled by
default even before we connected to the
internet or agreed to any terms or
conditions. Meaning it acts like a
claymore for your privacy as soon as you
trip it. And when a claymore says this
side towards enemy, that enemy is you.
This isn't new either. Lewis Rossman
pointed it out in his LG smart TV video
nearly 3 years ago.
>> If you go in any one of the default
profiles and you go to privacy and
terms, what you'll notice with a smart
television is there's an option called
do not sell my personal information. And
because we live in a dystopian world,
this option is not by default checked,
which by the way on a $3,000 LG OLED
should be opt in, not opt out for
tracking FULG for doing that.
>> Microsoft also took some, albeit
limited, action. Epic Games CEO and AI
lunatic Tim Sweeney alerted Microsoft VP
Pav Davaluri about LG monitors covertly
installing its app and showing ads for
McAfee. According to the Microsoft VP,
LG disabled the McAfee pop-up ad from
its app. Microsoft's lip service about
the problem said nothing about LG
installing its app without alerting
users in the first place. Nor did
Microsoft mention how its own subsidiary
partners with LG in its data management
and collection. With all of that
explained, let's get back to some of the
people we spoke to for this piece. We'll
start with Lewis Rossman, specifically
talking about forced arbitration, the
clause that was added after our first
video on LG's monitors, and he can
explain why that's a bad thing. I was
working on the LG monitor, their t TVs
for this story, the smart TVs, and I saw
something that immediately reminded me
of you, which is they have a sticker on
the back of one of the TVs we bought
that says forced arbitration notice. And
from what I remember, you you really
like forced arbitration clauses.
>> Yeah. I love giving up my seventh
amendment rights to a company in an
agreement that I never actually read.
And one of the reasons it's important to
say that you haven't actually read it is
because with their refrigerators, they
were telling people when the I forget if
it was the condenser or there was some
part of their refrigerators that was
failing and mass and LG was not
replacing it under warranty. So people
wanted to sue them and they said, "You
can't sue us because you agreed to
forced arbitration." They go, "What?
It's in the manual and it's on the box."
Now, when you buy a refrigerator, if the
box for the refrigerator is larger than
your door frame, what that means is that
you're never going to actually see the
notice because the delivery people and
mass were getting rid of the box and
throwing it away because most people
don't want to save the box of their
refrigerator, especially in a small
apartment. So, they never actually got
to see a copy of the notice that they
supposedly signed for. But what they
were referring to is that when you
received the refrigerator, you signed
saying you received it, but that
apparently also meant that you agreed to
the terms of forced arbitration in their
manual, which you hadn't read yet or and
on the box that you've never seen.
>> And that's and that's somehow legally
okay.
>> And some of these TVs, we noticed that
they don't have it on all of the the
sticker doesn't always make it on. So
>> that's where I would address it cuz how
many words is too many words? Is it
4,000, 2,000, 1,000? How many words do
you need to have where it is okay to
take away somebody's constitutional
right?
>> Can you explain briefly? So forced
arbitration in general, like what what
is that? Why do the companies want
people to agree to a clause for forced
arbitration?
>> If I screw over my customers, if I do
something horrible, they can either
commit acts of violence against me or
they can sue me. And that luckily most
people in New York chose the first one.
It's much cheaper than lawyers. No, I'm
kidding. But the if if I do something
wrong to my customers, they have the
ability to take me to court. And I think
that that is a good thing because it
means that it gives me an incentive
structure to treat my customers
properly. Forced arbitration means that
they sign away the right to that.
Instead of taking me to court, they can
take me to arbitration. Arbitration is a
court that I pay for. So, I'm paying a
mediator that's going to figure out
between the two of us, what are how are
we going to resolve this problem? And
the mediator being paid by me personally
is most likely going to have an
incentive structure to resolve issues in
a matter that I find amicable. And
they're also going to have an incentive
structure to screw me over in court.
Like there's a judge banging a gavvel,
right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> And there's
>> You mean it doesn't go through the legal
process?
>> Yeah. It's not going through the legal
process. There's no
>> It's an outside of court process.
>> And I can understand why people are
cynical. I get it. Class action lawsuits
cost money. How many people here have a
50-cent check on their refrigerator
because Visa and Mastercard them
and a lawyer got $20 million to handle
the case, right? Like how I have I have
checks on my refrigerator for less than
50. And they're annoying. And we roll
our eyes at the lawyers getting rich.
And that does suck that lawyers are
getting rich while consumers are not
getting help in those cases. And it's a
shitty system, but it's better than
nothing. So, for instance, when Apple
has a class action lawsuit against them,
even though it sucks that that the
lawyers got rich and that all you got
was some sort of $50 or $20 refund,
often times they'll say you must have a
repair program as a part of the
settlement. There'll be a repair program
for the butterfly keyboard. So, that's a
good thing cuz it's not just the the
check that you get on your fridge. Class
action lawsuits can often lead to
companies changing their behavior.
>> It's still a punishment for the company.
>> And not even a punishment, but it helps
the consumer. I'm not. So, a lot of
people will look at the 50 cent check
you get in your fridge, but they won't
look at Apple in 2015 deciding, you know
what? We are going to replace the
motherboard for free for anybody that
has an A1286, A20, 2915 board, but the
GPU died. We are going to replace all
the butterfly keyboards on the A706,
A707, and A708 models where it broke. We
are going to actually cover our
customers the way that we should have
been doing it before somebody
sued us. And that's better than nothing.
And I'd rather take that than just
removing my 7th amendment rights alto
together and saying that I'm not allowed
to sue. After after our video on the
monitors, the LG monitors, we noticed
that they updated the agreements, and
they added a whole big section talking
about class action lawsuits. And so,
they already had a thing buried in there
about you're agreeing that you can't go
through a class action process if there
is a dispute. So they already had that
there, but they added like paragraphs of
clarifying text that just continue to to
make that same point, which is like at
some point you're admitting guilt. I
feel like you're changing the terms when
there's a major class action concern.
Roku did this as well. There was a data
breach and they wound up sending it. Did
you see the notice where when you turned
on the TV, it said agree, but there was
no disagree option. So in order to use
the TV to change the input, you
need I'm pretty sure it was Roku. I have
an article. It was Yeah. Yeah, it was
broken. In order to change the channel
or change the inputs, you had to hit
agree. There was no disagree button. And
this happened at the exact same time
that there was a large data breach which
might cause people to push back against
it. I think it was Maine where they
filed the official notice of data
breach. I have the paperwork for this.
>> There's like 15,000 people that had
their data potentially breached.
>> Is there anything people should do? Uh,
you know, cuz a lot of these devices now
are going to have forced arbitration.
>> Be annoying. Take it to court anyway. Go
to small claims. Like there was this one
person Steven Ryan at the Vancouver stop
at the tour and he was saying companies
am annoying. He takes companies to court
for the stupidest And when I say
stupid, I don't mean stupid like it's
stupid he did it. I mean it's stupid
that the company is actually letting
this go to court instead of just
resolving the issue with the customer
instead of just helping them out. And I
like it. Like he said they found me
annoying. I said be annoying. We need
more people to be annoying. That's
great.
>> Progress moves forward because of
unreasonable people. Right. Right. If
>> if if 1% of your audience was was as
annoying as they needed to be, these
problems would all be fixed tomorrow.
>> Right.
>> Next, we'll speak with a surgeon we ran
into at Louiswis's event. Aaron was an
attendee there. He came up to speak to
me after I spoke with Lewis about owning
your And here's what he had to say
with concerns from the medical field.
>> You were Aaron, right?
>> Yep. A a r a yep.
>> Yeah. Okay.
And we were just talking, we were at
Lewis's event in South Carolina. We were
talking about LGTVs, which conveniently
enough, there's one right behind us.
>> So, so they'll hear this conversation
before anyone watching does. Um,
>> they're already listening.
>> What was, you know, what was
interesting, you mentioned to me, you're
in the medical field, I guess.
>> Yes, that's correct. Yeah, I'm a
healthcare worker. Uh, specifically, I
work in robotic surgery. So, I'm a
robotic general surgeon. Uh, just
finishing up my training. Uh I'm very
interested in tech. So like the merger
of tech and healthcare, you get robotic
surgery. Um my you know being techsavvy
and following you and of course Lewis,
my concern is is primarily in privacy.
Um
so what what happens when I'm taking a
patient phone call or I'm doing patient
uh video visits and there's an LG
monitor in the background? What happens
if it's doing it on a on an LG monitor
itself? Uh what's listening in? How is
that how is that patient information
protected? Because I'm expected to have
everything encrypted. Anything on my
device that has patient to do with
patients has to be through a VPN and
encrypted completely.
>> But if that is recorded and taken out of
my control,
>> who's to say that that's HIPPA
compliance or or anything? I mean there
there's a lot to do with you know how we
use AI tools and how specific ones need
to be HIPACO compliant if we're going to
use them as healthcare providers and
that's very clear but if LG is listening
to us on a TV where does that patient
information go obviously can't speak for
like all medical providers but um
broadly speaking with something like a
TV typically is that just like someone
just buys it for the office you know
like cuz cuz that doesn't strike me as
something like if you're going to use an
an AI transcription tool that strikes me
as something where administrative staff
or it or whoever would kind of go,
"Okay, we probably need to check for
HIPPA compliance."
>> Right.
>> Right. But something like a TV seems
like it's maybe send the assistant to
Best Buy or whatever.
>> Or if I take a patient phone call from
home, you know, I I I take those from
from my own house. And so I have a few
LG products before I watch your video.
And so where is that data going? I I I'm
not in control of that. I'm expected to
be, you know, advocating for my patients
and making sure that their privacy is
secure, but I don't even know who's
listening in my own household. And that
makes it very hard when I'm doing
patient care within privacy of my own
home.
>> I think that's one of the concerns we
have too is like LG's response is, you
know, is probably we're not listening
through the microphone and maybe the
capability exists, but they would say
we're not doing it. But one of the other
concerns we had doing this piece was um
if there's audio playing through the
speakers of the TV, there's also the
capability of capturing that or parts of
that.
>> And so you I I guess you know
>> probably tellaalth type of situations.
So I mean those are those are required
to be encrypted and if I log into
anything like Epic is our main Epic
Healthcare is our main um our main
electronic medical record EMR um when I
connect through that on my phone or on
my laptop it goes through a VPN that's
mandated by my employer
>> and so if it's being recorded outside of
that you know where that's not that's
not HIPPA compliant and so I don't have
any control over that cuz there's no
notice to me saying, "Hey, you're
actually being listened in on right
now." And so, how can I possibly be in
control of the entire environment when
everything else is being listened in on?
>> Have you tried putting tinfoil and lead
up
>> around like a Faraday cage around my
clinic? Yeah. Yeah.
>> Right. That would do it.
>> Yeah.
>> That'll be my next business. I'm going
to start selling fair cages for clinics.
>> That's great.
>> Yeah. I'll be your first customer.
>> Awesome. Thank you for the uh for
joining for the story.
>> Yeah. Thank you. I appreciate it. Next,
we'll check in with Kevin from the Fulu
Foundation. Kevin is the executive
director for the Fulu Foundation. He
works alongside Lewis at it. Kevin is
specifically pushing against DMCA
section 1201, which is a part of law
that makes it a criminal act in some
circumstances to circumvent digital
locks. He was also one of the organizers
for the Own Your tour that we went
on with Lewis. Here's his take on the
situation. My understanding is with the
digital millime copyright act, so DMCA
section 121 specifically, there's some
level of criminality, I guess, to
circumventing uh digital locks.
>> Yeah, that's exactly right. Right. So,
because of section 1201 of the DMCA,
simply circumventing a digital lock can
become a copyright crime.
>> Okay.
>> And so, when you're looking at these
cases, right, you've got your TV that's
spying on you, that's watching you,
that's listening to you, right? you
might want to go in and remove that
software. Sure, there are ways that you
can go through the menu and you can kind
of, you know, parse through the legal
ease and try and find a way, but there's
no way to know for sure, right,
>> that that data flow is stopping unless
you go in and take it out yourself. So,
because section 121 does have that
prohibition on the circumvention of
digital locks, um, you're screwed.
>> I guess if you could walk me through the
the basics of the DMCA and of section
1201 a little more, that would probably
help.
>> Yeah. So to do a little bit of the
history, right, the DMCA was passed back
in 1998 and the goal of it was to stop
piracy of media off of CDs and DVDs,
right? I would argue it was the wrong
solution at that time, but it's hard for
anyone to disagree with the fact that
it's the wrong solution for this time
because
>> Congress or the architects of this law
did not think that we would have
computers in our park pockets, that we
would have
>> computers in our cars, in our tractors.
Everything we use, right, pretty much
these days is a computer. And what that
means is that um those digital locks
kind of invade on our access to control.
So one analogy I like to use is right if
like if you bought a house,
>> you would expect to be able to get
through every door and get into every
room. One of those doors you
accidentally lock yourself out. Picking
that lock isn't breaking and entering,
>> right?
>> You own the house, you own the door, you
own what's behind it, right?
>> Because of section 121, that's a
completely different story for our
digital devices. If a manufacturer puts
a digital lock in front of a copyrighted
work such as yes, a movie or a song, but
also just source code or something like
that, um the mere act of cir
circumventing that becomes a copyright
crime.
>> And just as importantly, right, like I'm
sure that a lot of your viewers will be
able to go and do this yourself.
>> Um I'm a normie, so I can't do that. If
I wanted to hire someone to do it for me
or if someone were to try to make a tool
that would be easy for consumers to use
to go in and strip the ACR software off
of their TVs, um that would be again a
violation of section 1201. And that one
comes with serious penalties of up to
$500,000 in fines and five years in
federal prison per
>> seems proportional for
>> Yes, exactly. Helping people not get
spied on, right? helping people fix
their stuff um is just an outrageous
thing to be a copyright crime.
>> Lewis had in his presentation he showed
I think it was the author of I don't
know if it was the whole DMCA or Okay.
>> Yeah. He was one of the architects. So
Bruce Layman who uh worked in the
Clinton administration um you know he
did some interviews after the fact after
this law passed in 1998 and talked in
2007 and I think beyond that was first
of all said look
>> this law didn't work that well right
like Napster happened after the passing
of uh the DMCA so it didn't work the way
they wanted it to. Um and one of the
other things that was pretty shocking
was he talked about how you know he
basically executed an end run around
Congress. So, right,
>> when they first developed this idea,
this policy framework, they took it to
Congress and Congress said, "No, right,
this is going to get in the way of fair
use, right? This is going to infringe on
people's rights, on their ownership
rights, on all their kind of things,
those kind of things." Um, so instead,
he went and negotiated an international
treaty through what was called WIPO,
which is the World Intellectual Property
Organization, trying to solve this
problem. came back, went to Congress and
said, "Hey, we've got this treaty. If we
don't pass this law, we are going to be
not in compliance with this treaty." And
also, we're leaders in the world and we
need to do something about this, right?
So, it was just a total kind of pretty
questionable move if you ask me. Um, and
that's the reason that we, you know,
kind of sit here today.
>> Is there actually something people can
do? Obviously, we just, you know, we did
part of this tour I mentioned,
>> right? uh to try to get people to write
representatives and um I I think there
is probably a healthy and and earned
skepticism towards it but uh you know
actually trying to write to
representatives is probably one of the
only you know really good tools
available. It's really important, right?
Because I think there's a mixture of
things happening, right? People in
Congress, right? I I go to DC a lot as a
part of my job. And
>> many members of Congress don't
understand te technology.
>> Mh.
>> And at the same time, many don't
understand copyright law, right? Like,
okay, cool.
>> Which fair enough, right? Like if unless
you are into copyright law, you might
not understand it. Not every member of
Congress is going to be an expert on
every aspect of the law. But that makes
education that much more important and
it makes it that much more important
that they're hearing from their
constituents who care about these kind
of things. Right. So, as you mentioned,
right, we've got this tour. We're going
to 14 cities and states around the
country. We just had one of our biggest
in Raleigh last night, which was
awesome. Um, great crowd. And also, you
know, had a a member of the local
representatives office out to see all
>> she was listening. And she was
listening. Yeah. and she she did to her
credit uh she did seem to be engaged and
possibly on board with the idea of
owning your stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you know, I guess point of bringing
that up is
>> in the very least if not the
representatives it themselves then the
the staff might actually listen and you
just kind of hope that they filter the
message up.
>> Exactly. So, um, so for Fulu, we'll
point people there as well, uh, for
future tours and things like that, but
where should they go? And
>> yeah, go to fulu.org, right, to stay up
to date on our work. We've got our blog.
We post kind of, um, you know, regular
updates. Uh, we're also on, you know,
all all the social channels. Uh, one of
my favorite features is, right, the
consumer rights wiki is a big part of
what we do. Um, and so every week we do
the wiki hall of shame and highlight uh,
you know, manufacturers and products
that are particularly bad actors. So
>> there's so many options.
>> There are so many options. We could keep
going forever on this
>> infinite content.
>> Yeah. Um, but yeah, check us out there.
Um, and then get involved, right? We,
like you said, it's one thing when we as
an organization go there and that's our
job and that's, you know, we work really
hard at that. But when members are
hearing from their own constituents, it
goes that much further.
>> And finally, we'll check in with Wendell
for an extended discussion about our
findings. This was sort of our debrief
after working on the TVs for days. So,
some of the demos we had, can you help
explain what are some of the ways that
the findings, the vulnerabilities,
whatever could the features of the TV
could be used. Uh, for example, when the
TV appears to be off, but it's capable
of uh storing video and audio.
>> Yeah. Internally, the TV has 16 GB of
flash, which doesn't sound like a lot,
but it's got kind of a lot of
computational horsepower, especially the
newer TVs. And so, you can record audio,
you can compress it, you could stream it
to somebody over the network. It's a
full computer, so it's basically as
creative as your imagination is, you can
run stuff on it. Uh there's stuff on the
TV for like package management and
commercial customers of LG use a lot of
these features for like digital signage
and everything else like that, but you
know the consumer version of the TV,
they rip out some of those features and
some of the features that you know as
like homebrew enthusiasts and like home
lab enthusiasts, I'd like to have those
and LG takes that out. But you know
there's microphones, multiple
microphones there. Uh there is the
ability to read what is being displayed
on the TV programmatically. So you could
look, you could, you know, capture a
frame or capture short clips limited by
storage or streaming capability of
what's on the display. I mean,
theoretically, it's a whole computer. So
basically anything you can do with a
computer, but it's in the TV.
>> Even the places where we ran into
limitations, such as the few instances
where we had sixsecond recordings, I
feel like given more time than we had
here, it's it's possible a sophisticated
>> Yeah.
>> programmer could.
>> The TV is literally built for something
called automatic content recognition.
And it seems like the implementation
that LG uses for automatic content
recognition is designed to do six second
captures of what you're looking at. And
that's audio and video fingerprinting.
So when ACR is working as advertised as
the specification says, it's capturing
about 6 seconds of audio or video and
using that as a fingerprint and then
it's got a dormant period where it's not
capturing. And this is, I think, the in
the ad industry's hedge against
accidentally leaking, you know, hours of
conversations like, oh, we only capture
six seconds of it's enough to
fingerprint it, but that's still a lot.
You can do a lot with that.
>> You can do a lot with that.
>> Oh, it may also be a circumvention for
copyright law or something if the movie
studios are unhappy. What about so
fingerprinting? Walk me through that
because I think one of the security
researchers we worked with thought that
from his findings he couldn't see
evidence that uh ACR was necessarily
transmitting screenshots like JPEGs or
PGs.
>> You don't need to. You can take a a you
know if you're watching a 4K, you know,
Lord of the Rings, you don't need a full
frame. You can have a tiny tiny tiny
little frame and generate a hash of it
effectively. Effectively, it's a hash.
And then that hash is a very small
amount of text
>> and so that text can be sent back and
say hey this is the hash of the thing
that I see
>> and then what they they compare that
against the database and say this is a
frame from Lord of the Rings.
>> Yes. And we can see content of the TV
connecting to known Alonso that's one of
the name of the libraries and known
domains that have to do with automatic
content recognition. Um, and we can see
it downloading a thing that looks like a
database, like a fingerprint database,
which is, I think, some clues to the TV,
some hints to the TV about how it takes
that audio data and that video data to
generate the hash to then share with LG.
>> Why might they choose to do it this way
rather than send a screenshot or an
audio file?
>> Well, they did in the past. And you know
if you look at LG's history of security
issues uh you know 10 years ago almost
they were sending the raw file names and
then that turned into a PR incident.
Yeah.
>> And there is almost an adversarial
relationship with the TV here. If you
look at
>> how the software behaves like as I was
using it it changed behavior a couple of
times and I don't know if that was
because these TVs hadn't been on the
network and they were just downloading
application updates which is different
than a firmware update. Like I didn't
agree to a firmware update. Like I did
that very deliberately.
>> But even saying no, I don't agree to the
terms. No, I don't want to do this app.
It was doing stuff in the background
like downloading stuff for apps. Amazon
was doing stuff. The YouTube app was
doing stuff. It's like I don't even We
didn't even dig into what those
applications were doing.
>> Yes. You're not sure if it's because it
was downloading stuff or because it was
detecting your access basically.
>> Yeah. Cuz sometimes the TV would go to
sleep and then it would lose I would
lose network access. And then other
times the TV would be doing something in
the background. And so everything the TV
appeared to be off, but I had full
access to USB and I had full access to
run my programs. I had full access to
audit whatever was going on on the on
the TV.
>> And so I just I would like to know like
what what is LG doing? Can I audit this?
Do I have the tools to audit this? And
the answer was mostly no. It was an
uphill battle for me to like dig my way
out and figure out what it was doing.
Let's say worst case scenario, you turn
it into a listening device. That seems
pretty straightforward. You turn it into
a device to exfiltrate information from
a corporate network or a boardroom.
>> That seems pretty straightforward. Um,
you use it to maintain access like as a
point of presence on a network. Um, even
if you don't intend to capture audio and
video,
>> just to go through it, toggle through
it.
>> It is perfectly functional as a proxy.
So, you can proxy internet traffic and I
can just it's like, oh, I'm going to use
this to move laterally through
somebody's network. We've seen that in
the in security circles. We've seen that
with like copy machines. Uh certainly
the TV is is more sophisticated than the
copy machine that I am acquainted with
that was a command and control server
for very bad malware. So yeah, the kinds
of things we see in the news where it's
like oh fancy bear is attacking routers.
Uh fancy bear would be very comfortable
inside LGTV.
>> What about the scenario where the TV
speaker output uh could be captured? So
this was as we called it the boardroom
scenario.
>> Yeah. So, if you're using your TV as a
display, the HDMI audio that goes
through the display is also capturable
from the interfaces that we have on the
Linux side.
>> And this is something you proved that we
were able to do it.
>> Yeah, exactly. It's a feature, not a
bug,
>> right? And and this just to be clear
again like there because there's a few
links here, but you can do this without
your laptop and you being physically
connected to the TV directly. Yes.
>> Right. You can do this through the
network.
>> Yeah. And we can do it with the TV off
of the network and just have it capture
and then as soon as it gets network
access again, it was basically used as a
recording device,
>> right? You go back in after it's
reconnected. So, let's say you're super
paranoid, I guess, and there's a
scenario where you you not you just you
unplug the Ethernet from your TV during
this boardroom meeting or something. I
guess as long as it's still powered on
and capable of capturing,
>> you've got at least 4 gigabytes of space
to work with, right? So, if you had an
adversary that knew that there was going
to be a big important shareholder
meeting, um they could have the TV
completely offline off of the internet
and it's perfectly capable of recording
and storing the audio for that meeting.
And then somebody could come in later
>> as long as they've prepared for it in
advance. They know it's going to happen.
They set it to record. Yeah.
>> Whatever. shareholder. Someone's super
paranoid. They unplugged the Ethernet
cable,
>> but it was already rolling the capture,
I guess.
>> Yeah. For audio, uh, you know, it's it's
16 gigabytes total storage. You got
probably about 4 GB to work with out of
the box if you don't get creative.
>> And that is a that's 4 GB of audio.
That's a lot of audio. But imagine also,
I've got a 256 gig USB stick. I stick
that in there. That's weeks of audio,
>> right? Uh so in so in this example, you
know, the boardroom example, I guess,
use cases might be let's just take the
least nefarious I guess just just good
old like fraud basically market
manipulation.
>> Yeah. I'm going to I'm going to play the
stock market. What's going to be said in
this thing? There you go.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh which could be useful also to nation
states or, you know, intelligence
agencies. Like I'm sure there's all
kinds of stories of North Korea, for
example, doing things in the crypto
market or whatever. So
>> yeah,
>> um what
>> and if your TV like let's say that your
IT organization is like super on the
ball and the TV is normally not on the
network at all and it's completely
isolated and it's not even in scope for
them to monitor. If you had somebody
acting nefariously like that and they
had alone time with the TV, you could be
in and out in 10 minutes.
>> So yeah, so there's potential vectors
both on and off network, I suppose.
>> Uh and with and without physical access
depending on how you get in. Yeah, your
guy found a zero day that seems like it
would be able to connect to the TV over
the network uh non-interactively,
>> right?
>> Fabulous.
>> The one that we found requires you to
hit okay. It's like a mobile device
would like to pair with your TV. Is that
okay? And then you say yes. And then
that's all she wrote. All
>> right. Um what about the scenario where
a TV ACR audio capture? So we were able
to pull the 6second or so audio clips.
So this is separate from the one where
it's just the speakers for the boardroom
scenario.
>> Yeah, this was a little bit of creative
debugging. So like we really we were we
were we were up to our elbow inside the
TV if you know mental picture for that.
It's pretty amazing I think. and the ACR
process. So
>> colonoscopy of LG
>> we were we were running uh very deep
analysis of the ACR process and we were
able to see because this also helped us
figure out some of the audio formats
like some of the audio formats are
nonobvious. There's also a speaker
feedback microphone a secondary
microphone which could be used for audio
capture which we should talk about. We
were able to intercept the audio
recording before it was converted into a
hash and save it.
>> Okay. And so without and that sounds
like it's a lot of manipulation but like
once you know how to do that you have a
very very tiny program that's just
watching the other program and when it
captures the audio it's like yo that's
mine and you can save those sixsecond
clips and that would that's very hard to
detect.
>> Yeah
>> because the TV is is behaving normally
>> right.
What about um the feedback mic? You just
mentioned that. So, the feedback, the
audio quality from that is terrible, but
it seems like there is a secondary
microphone that's used somehow as part
of like the audio solution. I have no
idea how it's supposed to work in normal
scenarios. Uh, but it's very low bit
rate, which is good, but it's not low
enough bit rate that we couldn't
reconstruct speech from it.
>> Mhm. What about um log files on RAM? So,
that was pretty interesting.
>> Okay. So, it's only 16 gigabytes of
flash and it does seem like in So, I
started like full background here. I
started on an older TV. You You bought a
newer one. It's a donation to the cause.
I don't know. We're going to we're going
to run that in. Doesn't matter. Doesn't
matter. Uh my older TV um was a little
bit more uh verbose with logging. And I
think that LG probably ran into
situations where that was wearing out
the flash prematurely. Um, and so this
new one logs everything to RAM disk. But
there is a process that runs and
collects the logs, I guess, the
interesting stuff and puts it in flash.
There's also a lot of evidence in the
packet capture that this stuff is sent
to LG. And so in the debug logs, which
are stored on a RAM disc, and so even
when the TV is off, it doesn't erase
that. You have to like physically unplug
it or do something with that. Um, in
those logs, we can see everything that
you've said to the TV,
>> right? Uh, do you want to pull up an
example? This is stored in a log file.
Uh, I mean that's concerning for a
number of reasons. Devil's advocate
position might be okay, but you
explicitly said hi LG and triggered it
right before you so you knew it was
recording. But in fact, there were
several instances where genuinely we did
not know I didn't know it was still
recording. And so some of the testing I
was doing was it appears to be uh
somewhere between 10 and 15 seconds or
so it will remain active.
>> I just heard it ding.
>> Did you really? I that was the other
thing. We we got it working from at
least 60 ft roughly away, maybe 70
around a corner in some instances around
two corners. And
>> microphone's really good.
>> The microphone's amazing. It like we
should maybe replace some of our studio
mics. But the
>> that's another thing an adversary with a
little bit more time can figure out the
voice wake microphone. Now that also was
a little it was a little weird for us to
try to co-opt the voice capture
microphone, but clearly LG is doing
something there. And I feel certain that
uh an appropriately skilled security
researcher could co-opt that microphone
and get even better recordings than we
did.
>> Yeah. And I think really the key is it's
writing these log files.
Even if if you have ambient conversation
that's happening around the TV when
someone triggers it, uh it will remain
active if it continues to hear speech
for some period of time. It seemed
pretty long and uh it's it's collecting
all that and it's writing it here.
>> Yeah. This is without any modifications,
I think, is is what is what you're
you're getting at. Yes. It's like I I'm
co-opting the microphone to record audio
and we know that that the six-second
clips are destroyed in favor of but
these captures. Yes,
>> this is as the TV works.
>> Yeah, as the TV works, the text that it
was able to convert from your speech
ends up in the log,
>> right? So, as long as you can get access
to those logs, you can get access to
what was said. And once again,
>> it may be more than just, "Hi LG, please
change the channel." Yeah, it's funny
actually. Um I'm now I'm remembering
from like an IT audit standpoint. Uh one
of the things in like ISO, not not just
ISO, but like process certification and
um the California privacy law having
debug logs that log sensitive
information is verboten and this would
probably run a foul of that.
>> Well, we had uh an example where I said
>> right there.
>> So here you go. So here was now it was
triggered But then I I was started
talking about something else. I was
talking about my social security number.
Maybe I was on a phone call with a
hospital or something. I need to verify
who I am. Yeah. Whatever the case may
be, maybe a credit agency.
>> And uh I said, "Hi, LG." I told it to do
what I wanted. And then I continued my
conversation. Yeah. And here it is.
Here's my social security number. 11111.
The response to this I guess is
well first of all it appeared to persist
after we cleared we told it to clear the
data.
>> Yes.
>> And it persisted.
>> Yeah. So
>> there's one asterisk we'll get to. But
>> yeah, we clear it's like okay clear the
data. The TV treats that as let me just
phone LG servers and clear the data. It
doesn't really seem to do much locally
with that. Now, these logs, the full
verbose logs are stored on a on a RAM
disc.
>> And if you reboot the TV, it doesn't
clear the RAM disc, right?
>> But if you physically unplug the TV,
>> if you kill the power,
>> if you kill the power, it does. And so,
we lose this. They It also seems to
rotate these verbose logs pretty
quickly.
>> Um, but
>> if someone's pulling them though, yes,
>> in the in real time, it doesn't matter.
>> Yeah, it doesn't matter. Um, and it
seems like a lot of the applications and
like the applications that are
generating this that are doing this are
actually doing kind of a lot of writing
to the flash. Like it's it's still it's
like, oh, we've taken steps to
>> make sure that we don't prematurely wear
out the flash, but it's still doing a
lot. And so I think there's there's
there's a lot of fertile ground here for
researchers to go. It's like, okay, what
is it doing exactly? But most of the,
you know, delete my data or forget this,
it doesn't do it doesn't care what's on
the TV, right? It just does the remote.
>> Yeah. So, the the situation we were
concerned about was okay, if you do
delete my data, you bring the TV to
Goodwill and it's gone. Does that data
persist? Initially, we thought maybe
because when we rebooted it, it was
still there in the logs, but then after
pulling the power cable, it got wiped
out, right? Yeah. So, at least locally
to the TV, those specific verbose logs
appeared to be gone.
>> Yeah. But other logs persist.
>> Other logs were still there and we
haven't dug into every single one of
them. So we we can't say with certainty
like what it retained, but
>> yeah unsettling. It's like how do you
format your TV? LG doesn't. It's like do
you trust LG to do that? It's like no, I
would like to get in there and look
around and
>> make sure it's formatted. Yeah,
>> that seems reasonable.
>> What about um how does the TV know where
it is?
>> Uh so uh
>> there's no GPS. While other researchers
have sort of noticed that, hey, when we
look at the traffic to LG, it sure seems
like that it's inventorying the wireless
networks that are around. So, there is
no GPS unit. If you take it, it's like,
oh yeah, this is great. Even though I've
only ever used the TV for a wired
interface, it seems like it's noticing
the wireless networks that are around
it. And based on the wireless networks
you can see, you can use that for
geoloccation because you can see the
wire the names of the wireless networks
but also the MAC addresses of the access
points.
>> And that is a cheap easy way to do GPS.
I'll go you one better. If you had a
rogue employee inside of LG or a hacker
that leaks this database to the
internet,
>> so the information that that uh Mr.
captured
>> and was submitted. If that is in a
database at LG somewhere, then someone
could exfiltrate that information from
LG and now they can find a specific TV
based on interesting places the TV
exists.
>> Not like Washington DC or Yeah. Right.
>> Yeah. It's like I'm looking for the TV
in this boardroom. What do they have?
What are my options? And even before
setting foot inside the business, they
can know, oh, there's an LG TV there
because I have looked at the
geoloccation database in LG.
>> There's this 30 acre campus with nothing
but giant corporation A.
>> Yeah. Now, that sounds absurd, but if
you look at the if you set aside LG for
a second and look at Meta and how Meta
has sold ads, Meta has literally gotten
in trouble for uh selling to wouldbe
advertisers the ability to geollocate
down to like individual street
addresses. It's like I want to sell an
ad to the person in this house. Okay,
the the platform is capable of that.
>> There's so many ways to abuse that.
>> I don't want a TV that I have to have an
adversarial relationship. And
immediately out of the box, you're on
the wrong foot with LG because they own
the glass.
>> They do say they own the glass.
>> So, this is unencrypted. They don't even
try with this. This is just not even a
thing. If you're in the middle between
the TV and the internet, then it's a
command and control type situation. You
could also make the argument like if LG
lets one of those bazillion domains
expire, that's going to be a great
vector to take over tons of TVs. So LG
gets kind of a black market here, too,
because my older TVs have security
vulnerabilities that LG is just not
interested in patching.
>> Okay, cool.
>> They're like, "Oh, it's a six-year-old
TV or a 5-year-old TV. We don't care."
>> Right. Great.
>> Yeah. But if you have Yeah. Right.
>> Um RCE, so can you help explain some of
this where
>> Mr. bra has a vulnerability that we
can't disclose
beyond basically saying it's bad and uh
and it could grant someone access to the
TV. I think that's about the extent of
what we can say.
>> Yeah.
>> Um but can you help without exposing too
much of that information explain the
concept of like an what is you know
remote code execution? What is that
without going into how it works here?
>> So you're gonna you're going to show on
TV what we did using the stuff from
GitHub, right? Yes.
>> Okay. So that was remote code execution
effectively.
>> So you can use our work to explain it.
Okay.
>> Uh he found a way to do it
non-interactively probably,
>> right?
>> Which is amazing. Nice job. Uh the uh
the first uh attempt that we had failed.
And so we got the popup at the bottom
where it was trying to install, you
know, whatever it was, but it was not
able to um remotely execute all of the
code. It was able to remotely execute
some of the code to give us the banner,
but it wasn't able to remotely execute
all the
>> take a step back just like first I guess
definition of remote code execution
broadly
>> um
>> as a vulnerability
>> uh you can cause something to download
code and execute it with whatever level
of permissions. Okay,
>> so remote code execution, you might be
executing the code in a sandbox, but
then you might be able to escalate your
permissions from the sandbox to some
something else. And so this is this
that's uh more broadly described as like
exploit chaining. But rce remote code
execution is one of the best uh beach
heads into a system as like a starting
point. If you can find a vulnerability
that is remote code execution, then you
can get a lot more access to the system.
Um, the less interactive
>> uh requirements you have for remote code
execution, the more ability you have to
take over more TVs, okay,
surreptitiously, right?
>> So, the the the more holes that you find
sort of the worse it becomes.
>> That makes sense. Um, ours, the one that
worked was actually, I think, a worse
remote code execution than the one that
had been patched by LG.
>> The one that had been patched by LG was
we had to put in the um the IP address
of the TV
>> and then the TV would pair the the
exploit application would pair to the TV
like as if it was a mobile device. And
so there was a pop-up and we had to say
yes
>> and then it took off and that was fun.
Um, but that didn't result in control of
the TV. The one that worked was from the
browser in the TV. So like if you go in
the web browser in the TV and you went
to a web page
>> and you went to the wrong web page
>> and you accidentally hit yes or on
purpose was like a mobile because the
web page also generated
>> this one you ran.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
>> And so the popup said, "Oh, there's a
mobile device. Would you like to pair
with a mobile device?" There was no
mobile device. That was the web page.
The mobile device was the web page.
>> And so if you said yes because you know
the thing is a little fiddly. Or if you
just were in a loop and you said no, you
can just have it say yes over and over
again,
>> right? Until they finally like, h, fine.
Okay.
>> Yeah. The LG browser is not it's
terrible. And but it's Chromium based,
but it's old Chromium. And so it's um
and so you say yes and then we were in.
>> So that's really not a a really super
high bar for
>> right access. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And also LG doesn't give you like
their even if you go in their developer
program like that that's the legit way
to do this kind of thing. They really
don't give you full access to the
hardware that you own because they don't
think you own it.
>> Yeah. As we keep coming back to.
>> Yeah. And that's that's offensive. It's
like it's my TV. I'd like to audit it.
If if you look at the old TVs that we
have like six years ago, um those TVs
didn't even have an advertising ID out
of the box. And then you get a firmware
update and even without opting into
anything, boom, there's your advertising
ID. I didn't agree to that. What?
>> We showed it on your TV. Yeah. You
literally had no terms you had agreed
to, right? Yep. Ever. And then
>> from one update to the next, it's like,
oh, now we've got an advertising ID. And
you can't turn it off.
>> It added that cookies thing, too. Yeah.
The kind of dark pattern toggle. Yeah.
>> Like, I did not give you permission to
alter the functionality of the TV with
this update. there was no notice that
the functionality of the TV would be
altered with this update.
>> Right. Well, and that also seems like it
would require some kind of toos
agreement or something, user agreement.
But
>> even basic stuff, there's there's people
on on on the forum that have been raised
in heck because LG keeps changing how
they deal with DTS audio, and that has
nothing to do with any of the stuff that
we're talking about except for LG is
changing the functionality of a TV after
the fact,
>> right? All right. Any other any other
points you want to talk about here? I
mean, you're you own several LG TVs in
your office.
>> Yeah, it's basically all LG. Uh, it's
funny, though, because all the LGs that
I've had here for years, every one of
them is the out of the box firmware.
>> That's LG right there.
>> Yeah. Yeah. This is like the other one
that's on a they're all LG and yet
they've never been on the network
because I never I've never trusted LG to
do that. Actually, the crossover
monitor, the like the the the one on the
wall back there is an LG panel with LG
Alternative Electronics. And as a
company, Crossover, that was a viable
business model for them. We can actually
go peel the sticker off and there's an
LG sticker behind the Crossover sticker.
>> So Crossover is the name of a brand.
>> Okay. So Crossover put their sticker on
top of the LG sticker.
>> Yep. But it's a completely different set
of electronics.
>> Why? What's the
>> I think you know why.
>> You know, short version recap. How do
you feel about the what's your level of
concern with this, you know, as as both
a a business owner with these types of
devices, but also someone who may, you
know, advise or work with businesses on
security or infrastructure?
>> I've never advised using the TV's
built-in apps. It is it's a devil's deal
and eventually it will come to
>> but I have to admit that it was very
creative of LG cuz like a computer
display is a dumb display. It was very
creative of them to co-opt the Windows
update system to use that to in shedify.
>> Well, you know that uh Microsoft owns
the data management service that LG uses
for that stuff.
>> That tracks,
>> but don't worry, Microsoft will throw LG
under the bus and pretend that it was
all their fault.
>> Yeah, I like how Microsoft's reaction to
that was like, hey, could you maybe cut
that out and not just terminating their
Windows update account and rolling back
all the changes?
>> I mean, that's probably what they would
do to a small developer, right? some
name they would just terminate your
account like you've abused this function
goodbye you know but not
>> they certainly did that to the security
researchers trying to tell them problems
with things Microsoft
>> thanks Microsoft
>> all right I think that's kind of that's
a pretty good recap so
>> we'll jump over to the next part thanks
Wendell
>> thanks Steve
>> LG will probably say that they take
vulnerabilities very seriously and will
patch them right away but they didn't
reply to us when we sent them a ton of
our concerns. The bigger we
think, is LG deliberately designing this
to make money off of your privacy after
you paid for a thing and off of your
personal information. You have to reject
this outright or it will just keep
getting worse. If you want flock cameras
on your living room wall, this is how
you get flock cameras on your living
room wall. The only reason to give a TV
this kind of power is to visit horrors
upon you, not to make a better product.
Ultimately, we wouldn't recommend any LG
smart products to literally anybody.
That'll wrap this part of our deep dive
investigation. We do have more, though.
It's likely we'll have more installments
in this saga, and we really need your
help to pay for this video. I spent a
lot of money on this video.
Seriously, it was a lot. We spent more
than a month working on this, including
travel, buying thousands of dollars of
TVs. We had most the team on this
project. Really, the best way to support
us on this one and the other upcoming
videos in this series would be through
our data dragnet campaign on the store,
which is a Kickstarter style campaign
where we transparently show you how much
money we've raised. And we have some
goals what we're going to do with it.
So, for example, we'd really like to go
back in with Samsung, Vizio, anyone
else, and kind of do a bunch of this
research again or stuff like it. See
what we can find. This is so expensive
both in time and in actual cost and the
two related together. I mean, I can't
just like stop everything for three
months every time we do one of these
kind of like we did with LG. And so
that's where we really need your help.
We have some pretty damn cool stuff on
the store for this as well. So, in
addition to the individually available
items like our new foil cyber skeleton
shirt and our foil polygon V2 shirt and
our LG Investigation Blu-ray discs
available that we're burning in house,
we're 3D printing the cases in house.
all that stuff. We also have four
different backer tiers that give some
good discounts on bundling a bunch of
items together. They also give bonus
videos. And then in the case of the
sabotur tier, the highest one, there's a
live stream Q&A with me that you'll get
to join. I'll send those invites out at
the end of the campaign. So, be a little
while, but those are always really fun
to hang out with the community. So, this
is the best way to support us. If you
don't need one of these, we also have a
donate button in the bottom left of
store.gamersex.net
and on patreon.com/gamers
nexus for monthly support. Or you could
consider buying one of our other items
like our project and soldering mats.
Great for any project. We think the
extent of LG's data harvesting is
intrusive and grotesque. Additionally,
despite the Overton window shifting
further and further away, we still
believe that when you purchase
something, especially for thousands of
dollars, you should own that thing. LG
isn't the only smart TV manufacturer
behaving this way. and we'd like to
expand the scope of our investigation
and eventually test TVs from other
manufacturers in a follow-up piece, but
we are going to need funding for that.
If you have any tips or leads for a
follow-up, please email us at
tips@gamersex.net.
Mr. Bra advised immediately
disconnecting LG smart TVs from any
network. Wendell felt much the same. Our
other researcher we worked with, U-Turn,
said this quote, "My recommendation to
users would be to demand ownership over
your devices. First, by using and
supporting proconsumer projects that
seek to give you device control back,
and second, by demanding legislation
that reflects the changes you want to
see. Sell carriers only carrier unlock
your phones because the 113th Congress
made it law." End quote. Which I thought
was an excellent point. As where groups
like Fulu come in both U-Turn and Mr.
Bruh have communityf funed coffee pages
we'll link below. Our thanks to Wendell,
Mr. Brah, and U-Turn for their help with
researching this piece and the
informants in our inbox. We'll have a
lot more to talk about with all this
soon. And one final time, we really do
need the help funding this expensive
type of work so we can do the next set
of smart TVs. So, if you feel like you
can spare it, please head over to our
store or Patreon to leave a super thanks
below so I can spend thousands of
dollars on TVs that will spy on us.
Thanks for watching. Subscribe for more
and we'll see you all next